Mayank: Before we move forward, few things.
Mayank: So, everyone, I'm sharing my screen. Let me know if you're able to see it. So, the main link which we have, right? I hope all of you are able to see my screen.
Mayank: Great. Cool. So, this is the link which we have, everyone. I have added another job opportunity, if you will notice. So, again, you have to make sure that you are eligible. This is, again, with a direct contact I know. So, someone whom I know personally. That person is looking. So, of course, a few people got a call from Kumar as well. Here, as well, you will be getting the call, provided you are.
Mayank: going like you are eligible for the job. Okay. So again, since I know them personally, the people who are looking for, it's just make a lot more sense that you can, you should use this up. Two job opportunities are there, direct referral, work from home, minimum experience is around five years. Pay will be 20 plus LPA. Please send email to this email.
Mayank: Subject should be your name, then the role which you're interested in, and the year of experience. Once you click on this, everyone, I think you know that how you will be able to use the same, okay? So, okay, I hope that works. Also, many of you might like have sent me emails. Few I have replied, few I will be replying. So yes, okay, just give me some time.
Mayank: There were some emails replied. If you, I will be replying as well every month. Great. Cool. So can you change the headers of slavers as we move on? That for listening to recorder will be easier. I'm not sure how to do that from my end. I like the way you are able to see it. If you would just send me a screenshot and like something on my email ID just right now, what exactly you meant, I can try it out. Okay.
Mayank: Minimum experience in relevant domain. Yes, of course, like that is the idea. So here it is, three to six years. If you will see everyone, senior AI engineer. So please make sure that you are sending it up. Don't send email here. Send it directly to me first because as I mentioned, I will be sending it up. And what I will do is I will just make it a little light. Let me not be this much. So minimum experience is going to be four plus experience then. Okay.
Mayank: Great. So, this is the first thing. Second, everyone is regarding something which Krishna asked. You can sign up on this Mesh API. So, we are trying to get some extra credits with all of you. So, yeah, this Mesh API, everyone is kind of like OpenRouter, where with a single link, we can access multiple models, etc. So, yes, we are trying to get some extra credits for all of you.
Mayank: By showcasing that, yes, we have a good student pool, so do sign it up, and yes, we will try to get the same for all of you. Otherwise, as well, you can check out the same. Okay, so that's the second thing, and I think, yes, we can now start. Okay, $16 class is not updated on GitHub yet. I think I've given the file, Abhiraj, if you are mentioning around the complete way we are having.
Mayank: That might not be present. Like, I think all the classes and everything is present, right? Cool. If you go on GitHub, I just might have to add the file, but that actually I will add after doing the same in depth. So.
Mayank: Yes, 16th August, I will just get the thing. Okay, you refer GitHub mostly, extremely sorry. I will try. Actually, I have to get this transcript up and create the same for all of you, the summary and everything. So, that is something which I'm waiting for. Once that happens, I think I will share that up. Okay, cool. So, something like this, I want to make sure that I can create up. So, that's the benefit.
Mayank: Great. Cool. So, yeah, both the links are present, everyone. Also, I hope all of you have seen this. I added this before as well. 26 September would be a holiday. Okay, 26 September would be a holiday. Cool. Shalom. Great. Let's begin, everyone. So, let's quickly talk about where we are and what we are going to do so that you can get a very good idea. Let's see.
Mayank: So, our topic for today has to be MCP, but there are two quick topics which I would love to cover before. So, before we jump onto MCP, I would love to cover about runtime and human in the loop, okay? Great.
Mayank: Human in the loop. It's 26th September, everyone. 26th September. A month from now. Okay? 26th September. So, 26th September. Okay? Good.
Mayank: Cool. So let us go back to the documentation, everyone, and let me show you, like, what exactly and how exactly we will be doing it. We have done till custom middleware. You have got an assignment as well. I will be giving the solution of the assignment by next week. Okay, so I hope that is fine. Everyone has got the assignment, yes or no?
Mayank: Each and every one of you got the assignment. It is there present on multiple places like GitHub, CraftLink, everywhere. We are taking two weeks on every assignment. So yeah, once you do that up, I think you all will be able to see and get the solutions as well.
Mayank: Again, it is very nicely visible, everyone. I'm not sure why you might not be able to find it. Assignment 2 added 16th August. Assignment 2, agents and payment middleware. Assignment, LangChain fundamental solutions. This is the Google Pollab notebook. Okay, so that is the case. Then, after that, everyone, we will be now jumping to this advanced usage. In the same, we kind of did context engineering already.
Mayank: Although I will be explaining the same to you otherwise as well, a little bit more in depth, but not right now. I think we have did the same as well. Guardrails also we have understood and seen. Okay, so you can have a quick read. Runtime is something which I want to explain you. That's a little bit of important topic which I feel should be explained. And same goes for this human in the loop.
Mayank: Then you see this topic, everyone, MCP Model Context Protocol. How many of you see this topic, MCP Model Context Protocol? Great. So this is where I will be taking a deroute. What do you mean by deroute, Mayank? So I will be making sure that I explain you MCP complete in depth, irrespective of LangChain.
Mayank: and here we will be learning the complete MCP architecture second create your own MCP third MCP like there are two things to it client and server okay client and server and third we will make sure that we are able to understand in depth plus.
Mayank: Publish on cloud. Publish on cloud. Okay. So I hope this works everyone. And this is going to easily take us around three classes, minimum three classes. I'm saying minimum. So towards the end, we will shift towards Landshare on how to use it, but I will be covering this in depth. So it's a very good opportunity for anyone who have missed out on the.
Mayank: LangChain understanding — highly suggested to do that because after this, we will first be doing a project. Then we will — actually, in that project, I'm using MCP, so I want to make sure that you understand the same in depth as well. And then I think we will jump to multi-agent. And yes, then I think LangGraph, etc. The project would be done on GCP, but I will keep you updated on that. Okay, I will give you the code and everything.
Mayank: So yes, I hope the future class flow is clear. Everyone, yes or no? Future class flow is clear.
Mayank: Great. I hope all of you understood that MCP we will be doing in depth. Now, when I talk about in depth, I mention about the complete MCP thing, irrespective of LangChain. Because I have used MCP where I have created a MCP server that is being used, that is something which I will be planning, and we will be doing a project on GCP.
Mayank: So again, that's why I'm saying minimum three, not three hours, three weeks, like three, three classes. Sorry, my bad. Minimum three classes because we will be taking a T route to make sure we can understand MCP in depth and then move forward with the complete understanding because it'll be again, same for every other framework. It'll be very easy, like using MCP is easy, creating is very difficult. Okay. And then yes, we will be jumping to your.
Mayank: Project on GCP, everyone. The project I will be explaining as we move forward, I will be explaining what are those small, small things. A few of you will be learning yourself, like I will let you know what exactly is there and everything because, yeah, I think that will be more than enough. Great. So I hope that thing is clear, everyone, till now. Anyone has any doubt before I move forward? If you're happy, just stay calm. Don't send a smiley face as of now.
Mayank: This one, no. Okay. When will we start RAG and embedding? After the project and multi-agent. Okay. So the natural flow is that we are moving and we are covering these topics up. Just that you will notice these things pop up everywhere. So when we will come to RAG, everyone.
Mayank: We will just understand about the RAG, and we will make sure that we are able to dive deep into it. That's my philosophy because, ideally, if I could make you a champ in understanding one framework, okay, one framework, if we are able to understand one LangChain LangGraph, let's say, taking that as one framework, then you will see that all future ones are very, very similar and very easy. Okay, so that is the whole approach, so don't worry on that.
Mayank: And yes, then I think we can cover any number of frameworks, AutoGen, Agent SDK, anyone. That should not be a problem. Okay, so cool. I think that should be more than enough. Let's move forward with that, everyone. So that is the philosophy, but I think you can be rest assured you don't have to worry. You are seeing how much depth we are covering the topics. You have nothing to worry. Okay, let's be assured you are in good hands. So that should also not be a problem.
Mayank: Great. So now let us move forward everyone. Let me open another one on this notebooks up. Our project is going to cover each and every concept. Yes, of course. That's the idea. That is why I'm teaching you in depth, right? So I have to make sure that you are able to understand the project completely. I will be sharing the file of project code of project by maybe next class.
Mayank: like next week. Okay, if you don't know GCP, don't worry. You should be eager to learn. I will be teaching you when we will be using it. Cool, sure. Let's move forward then, everyone. Should be fine. Great.
Mayank: Now, let's move on to the next topic, everyone. And that topic is going to be, do we do project in AWS and Azure afterwards? Like, first, you will start with GCP. It gives you three months of free things, so I think all of you can take the benefit. And yeah, then I think it should be pretty good. Cool. See, I cannot do a project in every place at once, right? I cannot do a project in GCP, Azure, AWS, all at once. So, it doesn't matter. Give me time.
Mayank: Be worry free. Should be all fine. Great. So now I want to talk about something which is very, very important again, and that is known as runtime and rather state as well, because when I was revising the last class, which I took, many people were facing problem in that. So let me quickly help you to understand and revise.
Mayank: Now, the best part, everyone, we are doing things in lots of depth so that not only are we able to create agents, we are able to control our agent a lot. Now, when you want to control your agent, the whole approach becomes that, okay, how much in-depth do you know about these different things?
Mayank: Not just with respect to the framework. So it should not that, hey, I know how to create an agent in LangChain. No, that is a very wrong statement to make. Can you say that you know otherwise what an agent is now, everyone? I think it has been around for two months, but now you know what an agent is, what an AI agent is.
Mayank: It kind of doesn't matter where we are creating it. So that should be a very good thing. Second is that you should not be limited by what a framework provides. For example, tomorrow, if a framework does not provide that, hey, you cannot maintain a state, you should still be knowing that, okay, what exactly these things are, why they are useful. Because when we jump onto creating real.
Mayank: Agentic applications in biggest of the companies, in the job requirements which I'm sharing with all of you, it becomes a lot and lot of sense, okay? So, with respect to that, everyone, let's now understand and help me, help me, like, let me help you revise what exactly was agent state. We have covered the same, but still, I told you that how, and let us have the runtime of the topic.
Mayank: Very quick typing. I can have AI agent icon. This one is pretty good.
Mayank: Before I move forward and go on runtime, let us quickly state something which we need to understand, like which we need to kind of revise. Because in the middleware, I mentioned many times that, hey, how you can change the state, access the state, have the runtime. So on that note is what we are controlling, discussing it. Every agent manages its execution context through agent state, a type dictionary that holds current conversation history and any custom fields.
Mayank: your tools and middleware needs. So in a very, very simple sense, everyone, I can say that my agent, it is having a context, and this context will have conversation history and any overall variable. So I hope this thing is clear.
Mayank: that from here, I could mention that a type dictionary holds the current conversation history and any custom field our tools or middleware would need. Now, if you will notice, everyone, field messages. So, by default, it is having the messages field. We have covered about messages in depth as well. Agent series is also a type signature for every node-style middleware hook. So, before model and after model.
Mayank: They receive this agent state. Okay, hooks receive the current state and can return a dictionary of updates to merge back into. So I think now we are aware of the same, and this is where it was getting used. And I saw that many people were getting confused. When I was on custom middleware, and we were somewhere here, we understood that how it is getting this state. Node style hooks, they were getting this state. Right, everyone?
Mayank: So I hope now it is making a lot of sense that what exactly this state was, what we were receiving. Yes or no? Able to understand? And what you can also do, what you can also do, you can expand that state. You can say that, hey, I want to send other information as well. I have to send other information as well.
Mayank: which you can create by expanding the agent state, creating your own state class, and just having whatever you want. So, very simple approach. Context is having your variable and the conversation history. Sorry, this is state, which is having it.
Mayank: Conversation history and variables. So let me copy this up. Let us cut it up. Move this. Paste it here. So state is having conversation history and any overall variable. We can create our own state by expanding or.
Mayank: Inheriting.
Mayank: inheriting the agent state okay so I'm saying that hey if you inherit or extend the agent state so it should be a agent state type of an object you can create your own state your own state you can have any other variable as well as well which you want so I hope this thing is clear everyone this thing I hope is very much clear that how.
Mayank: By default, an agent in LangChain maintains this, and then we can have, if required, extended as well. And of course, if it is having it, middleware and other things can receive this state so that they can use it and get information, okay? So this is something which we saw, that how we can send our own state and everything, so that should not be a problem, and just telling our agent around it.
Mayank: Okay, and yeah, now I think we are good to run to runtime. So this is something just a revision because runtime and states gets used a lot, like in any framework, again, in use. Now, if you will notice, everyone, let's talk about runtime. LangChain create agent runs on LangGraph runtime under the hood. So very state, very first thing.
Mayank: That, of course, we have seen that whenever things are getting complex, that is where LangGraph is kind of doing the heavy lifting. In this as well, everyone, in this case as well, LangChain create agent, it is based on the LangGraph runtime. This LangChain's create agent runs on LangGraph's runtime.
Mayank: And it exposes few things which you can use. Now, LangGraph gives you a much closer approach, which we will see when we will cover LangGraph in depth again. But the idea is that your agent, when it does start, it is…
Mayank: Of course, having a runtime. So when it is running, it maintains a runtime. Everything, everything does. If you are code or anything, we say that runtime error is coming. That means that they are maintaining that, hey, what all is happening. So that is all what your runtime is, everyone. Nothing else. Whenever an agent runs, it will be having something during the run which it maintains, which you can access.
Mayank: which you can make sure that you are able to change as well if required. It has a runtime, so I hope this thing is clear. As the name suggests, runtime.
Mayank: As the name suggests, runtime. Okay?
Mayank: Now inside my runtime, and this is where it gets pretty fun, we are having lots of things. So let me just get a Mermaid 2 example. Let me get this. See everyone.
Mayank: Let me quickly get this. Yeah, we'll be seeing example for everything. Don't worry.
Mayank: Okay, so…
Mayank: Wait, let's see the same. LangGraph exposes runtime object with the following information. Context, static information like user ID, DB connections, or other dependencies for an agent invocation. So we are seeing that, hey, we are using the runtime. We know that, I hope everyone is clear that LangChain is built on top of LangGraph. That, I think, hierarchy is clear to everyone.
Mayank: I hope this thing is clear to each and every one of you, that LangChain is built on top of your complete LangGraph. LangGraph runtime, which it maintains, we are able to use the same as well. It is not reversed. Till now, you should be clear. LangGraph is like the lower one. On top of it, LangChain is there. And on top of that, DeepAgent is there, but let's see the same.
Mayank: Context, static information like user ID, DB connection, or other dependencies. Store, a base store instance used for long-term memory. So I hope all of you remember how we used to send the in-memory store, everyone, right or wrong? In-memory store, we used to send. Steam writer and object used for steaming information via the custom steam mode, so we can send and exchange the information when it is running.
Mayank: Execution info, identity and retry information for the current execution, thread ID, run ID, attempt number. Now, what happens? And pay attention here, everyone. See, when you're having an agent, in LangGraph, that agent is something like a graph, okay? In graph, we have nodes, everyone. In graph, we have nodes.
Mayank: For each of these nodes, they have some information which is maintained in the runtime, which we might want to use. For example, each and every one of these nodes can have some ID. They can understand how many times they have retried. Let's say that your code was running. It got stopped in between due to some reason. When you resume the same, it maintains that, "Hey, I was in the running state." It was not stateless.
Mayank: So now the whole idea becomes that whenever something runs, it maintains its runtime. Similarly, when your agent runs, everyone, it is also maintaining a runtime. I hope this thing is clear that if your agent is running, it maintains a runtime. Is this idea clear that when your agent is running, it is maintaining a runtime? Your runtime, it is having these five things up.
Mayank: In LangChain, it is saying that, hey, I am having these five things up, which you can use, which you can change, with which you can have some information and everything as well. So now let's move forward and let's see the practical. I think that would make a lot more sense. So let's go to this one. Quickly, let me get the initial things up.
Mayank: So let me share the same everyone.
Mayank: Share, share, share, share. Check out, share.
Mayank: Okay. Not this hosted panelist. Let me know with everyone. Cool.
Mayank: Let's do this again.
Mayank: Cool. I have shared the same everyone. I think you should be able to get it now. Okay. So you should be able to access the same. Cool. So let me quickly set it up. Let us quickly install a few things up.
Mayank: And MCP we will be doing in VS Code, everyone, so do make sure that you have that set up, okay? MCP we will not be doing in that, so that should be helpful.
Mayank: Mother, we will not be creating it on collab. Okay. So I will see that how can I share the code which I'm doing on VS Code rather than GitHub or GitHub will also work. But yeah, let us see that.
Mayank: All the keys are done there.
Mayank: When will we start RAG? I think I already told that. It's not that difficult. So when I will start RAG, I will do that in depth as well, okay? Or maybe I will teach you LangGraph first because then people will hate me. So we will get a basic idea maybe first.
Mayank: Mmm.
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: One minute, wait a minute.
Mayank: You're going to have a mistake.
Mayank: cool so let us just quickly check the connection doing it every time so you also are aware of the same okay cool so let's do that we can use OpenAI GPT-5 Mini.
Mayank: Cool. So now we are connected, everyone. Now let's quickly first understand. So till now, we were understanding every concept with the mini project kind of an approach where we were having a Cinebot, everyone. I hope all of you understand that. We were having the Cinebot. Yes or no? We were using Cinebot. Now.
Mayank: Let's first understand the problem. Okay, see your bot everywhere. It needs to have access to something which is not part of your conversation. So there was a conversation which you were maintaining, but I hope all of you will agree that there were a few things which were not part of the conversation. What were those things? Well, which customer is talking, like who exactly is talking to my agent, whether they are.
Mayank: VIP or not? VIP or not? Then which, let's say, cinema location this session is for? Okay, which exactly location this session is for? Now, if you think about this, don't you feel that these are some information which we need to have everyone?
Mayank: When you open ChatGPT or Claude, they know that which are you a pro tier or not, what is your name, what is maybe your preference or anything, but I think that comes up in the memory part. But otherwise as well, few information is required, right or wrong, everyone. And this information, if you think about it, don't you think that they should be able to travel to tools or middleware as well? These information should be able to travel to tools.
Mayank: Or, say, middleware. I hope this makes a lot of sense. So, these are not your conversation history, but these things are required, right? And that is where, as a solution, everyone, so if, like, this is all kind of the problem, then that is where, as a solution, I have something which is known as runtime. So, I hope now it is clear.
Mayank: that not only is it required that it maintains conversation history, it should be able to have some information which is not part of the conversation history. Clear, everyone?
Mayank: As an example, if, say, a patient is there in a hospital, we maintain a chart, the complete history. Sorry, we maintain a chart, and normally you will notice that how we have a wristband, right, everyone? A patient is having a wristband so that any department in which the patient visits, okay, any department in which the patient visits, they can all read the same wristband.
Mayank: Rather than patient explaining every time, so that patient, everyone, so if you are having a patient, not sure how many of you have seen this, let's hope you are not aware of that. That would be helpful, though it will kill my analogy, but should be fine. See, whenever you get admitted in a hospital, everyone, they make you wear a wristband. They say that, hey, wear this wristband up. Now.
Mayank: It is having some information where you can go to different departments, be it the ER doctor, the pharmacist, any nurse. They can read this statement, and they can actually understand exactly who you are.
Mayank: any information about you, what room you are in, all these things without asking you again and again. So not the part of a conversation history, but maintain otherwise overall. That is the whole idea. Okay, so that is the whole idea. Now let's discuss about the components, everyone. What exactly are the components? See.
Mayank: These are the five components which are maintained in the runtime. So whenever your agent starts, these five things are there in the runtime. And every code or software maintains a runtime when it runs. So component one is context, everyone. For example, it is static. Every run, it maintains a context, user ID, DB connections, any config, et cetera. Second is store, long-term memory surviving across separate sessions.
Mayank: So I think we have seen about the in-memory store. That is actually what we can use here. Steam Writer, a channel for custom progress updates during a run. So whenever your agent is running, it can have a Steam Writer where it can have anything which it wants to update, what all it has done till now, which will not be part of conversation history, but otherwise might be needed. Execution info, thread ID, run ID, retry attempt number.
Mayank: Server info, it is mainly for LangGraph server-only metadata, so that we can kind of go through for the time being. But yes, these are all the things which we maintain every month and which we get. Now, let's try to understand one by one what and how exactly we can use it. See, when creating an agent with CreateAgent, you can specify a context schema to define the structure of the context stored in the agent runtime.
Mayank: So, in a way, LangChain has provided you with a skeleton. You can just chain that skeleton as and when required. A very good example of this, let's try to create one only. I am seeing, so I am seeing everyone that my Cinebot, it will be having, so I can use data class here, class Cinebot.
Mayank: Cinebot Context, and it is going to have a username, which is going to be string. I can have actually cinema or maybe location as well, or maybe let's say geographical state, which can be string as well. What do I mean by geographical state? So it can be Delhi.
Mayank: or Bangalore, or Chennai. So, when you open any of your BookMyShow or anything, it understands these things, and these are the ones which can be used. Now, when we are defining the agent, everyone, so now this is where it gets more helpful, and I will just quickly import a few things up, which we have already used. PlantChain, chat models, and all these things, so kind of we have used it already. I can now define my agent, so I've defined my context, okay?
Mayank: Now I could make sure that this thing, okay, this thing can be created like this. So I have a agent, let's say agent with context. Let me call it agent with context. Like it was having some inbuilt things. We have just extended the same. See model.
Mayank: OpenAI GPT-5 Mini, not giving any tools. Context schema, Cinebot Context. Declare the shape of context this agent expects. Cool. Okay, man, how is this helpful? Well, now what I can do, everyone, I could just have a agent with context. I could invoke this agent, role user, content, what's my name, and I can pass this thing up. Let me make it this, let me, for the timing, just.
Mayank: Yeah, and I can pass these things up. So I hope this thing is making a lot of sense, everyone, that how I'm just passing it up. I don't need to have this in the conversation history or something, but yes, I am just making sure to pass the same up. And in this manner, I can maintain lots of things. And now I can print the result as well.
Mayank: So again, we have not parsed it as of now, so it is not going to say that. It doesn't get parsed automatically. We have to control that, but yeah. Cool.
Mayank: Able to understand that how and what it is going to maintain everyone? Able to understand that? Let me repeat for the time being so I don't get confused. We have to still use it, okay? We have to still use it. But we are able to have that. Now let's see that exactly how or where we can use the sync. Why I didn't tell the name? Because we have not used it as of now. We have to make sure that if required, we have to use this information, okay?
Mayank: It is just getting passed for the timing. We have to use the same. And now, let's see where all it can be used. Now, if I show you, this is the diagram, everyone. So, it can be used in tool, in middleware hooks as well, okay? So, these are the five things which it is having. Let's see the same, let's see the use by tool, something which we have seen already. So, now pay attention. Let me add a tool, and let's say that runtime inside.
Mayank: tools. It is something known as tool runtime altogether. So, when we are using runtime inside a tool, so let's see this. What I will do here, everyone, pay attention. I will just zoom it in a little bit. Data class, I will say class customer context in a similar manner, and say that it's a user ID. Okay, I can save it.
Mayank: From langchain.store.memory, import in memory store. And I can say loyalty.store.
Mayank: store equals to my in-memory store in where I will be maintaining all these things up. So, wherever it will be, sorry, it is in LangGraph. We have done this LangGraph. Okay, so LangGraph store memory, I'm importing the store and I'm defining it. Okay, now pay attention everyone that how we will be using this runtime. So, let me define fetch customer.
Mayank: preferences. Okay, and I hope all of you remember that when we did tools, and now it will make a lot of sense again when it will get continued, I told you that how you can access the context inside the tool. Tool can access runtime information through the tool runtime parameter, which used to provide all of these things. I hope it makes sense. I hope all of you are able to remember it.
Mayank: that when the tool gets run, everyone, you are able to get the information about runtime via this tool runtime, which is passed by default. So every tool, whenever you are defining it, it gets this tool runtime. In this tool runtime, you are having all this information. So I hope this thing is making sense that how you are having state is a separate thing. State.
Mayank: But along with that, Context, Stores, Team Writer, Execution Info, Server Info. Aren't these five things the one which we talked about? If you all remember, these five things are the one which we talked about.
Mayank: right? All these five things. So, when your agent runs and when it calls the tool, when it calls a tool, it is actually able to run, get all these information about your runtime. So, let's see now how it will be useful. So, let's see the same in it. So, how we are using it for the tool in the timing. This tool.
Mayank: Agent start, when it runs up, it is having a runtime. It is passed onto your Kuldeep even as tool runtime. As tool runtime. Okay? So, this goes…
Mayank: to your tool. Now inside tool, you can use the same. So let's go back and let's define it. So fetch customer preferences, I will, I can get this runtime and it will be of tool runtime and the state will be of, sorry, context will be of this type tool, customer context. And I can say that, okay, you are going to return a string.
Mayank: Now, of course, I could have this information. So let me get user ID, everyone. It can be runtime.context.userid. I hope now you are able to understand how subtly this thing is useful. Don't you think that you should have some way through which you can pass this information up, and it can be then used inside your logic?
Mayank: You should have some ways through which this information can be passed up, and you can use it inside your logic. This is that way. How it is used in real life? You go to Claude. Whenever you start a chat in Claude, new chat gets initiated. All your information with respect to these instructions, which you have given your name and everything, they become part of your runtime. And in future, then that is how Claude is able to.
Mayank: use that information. And without even you sending a single message, if I just send a hi, Claude has made sure that, okay, this is what it is maintaining. Hi, Mayank, what are you working on today? So I hope this thing you're able to understand everyone, yes or no, how your short-term, long-term memory, all these things connect. Okay, so.
Mayank: Agent starts with the runtime. We can control in that runtime context and everything. Then that same runtime, along with extra information, get passed to your tool as tool runtime. So that if required inside any tool, you can have this tool runtime which can be used, and then you can make its behavior the way you want. So, again, I hope this thing is clear, everyone. Yes or no? This thing is clear.
Mayank: Quickly, I will help you revise because this is a little bit of not so straightforward context because things are happening in the backend. Okay, this is a little bit of concept where things are not right in front of you. See, your agent, okay, again, again, make sure that you understand this, everyone, your agent, when it starts up, when it starts up, it is not just starting up with an empty mind. It is not saying that, hey, I don't know anything.
Mayank: I think Jon Snow was the person. I'm Jon Snow. I don't know nothing. Langchain gives you that we are going to start your agent up. It's going to maintain state. It's going to have.
Mayank: runtime, runtime, and if as a user, if as a user, so I could have this user.
Mayank: You can have or access them and pass some other info in the backend or background to maintain or to use the same. So, LangChain says that, hey, I will be starting your agent up. It will be having some state, runtime, and other things. In the runtime, now we have five things up.
Mayank: And I will be, as a user, you can, if you are very smart, you can use these things up to give the better functionality and everything. Now, at places where it will be used, everyone, for example, calling a tool, it is duty of LangChain that it is passing these things up. It is duty of LangChain that it is passing these things up.
Mayank: The very first thing, for tools, it says that, okay, I will connect these two things up and some extra information, and I will just pass the same as tool runtime, which every tool will be able to access. If you will be able to access this, then you will be able to add some extra functionalities and everything.
Mayank: I hope that makes sense. Now, if any one of you think, then why can't we directly use the runtime? Why the tool runtime? Anyone who is thinking this? Anyone who is thinking this? Well, see, this is the thing. LangChain is a framework, everyone, which has already been created by LangChain people. LangChain is a framework created already by LangChain people. It is sending the tool runtime. I'm not controlling that. It is sending that. See, it is written here. If you will go here.
Mayank: Tools can access runtime information through the tool runtime parameter. So when your tool gets, when you are using something as a tool, it is getting this tool runtime parameter. I am not controlling it. LangChain is saying that, hey, I will send a tool runtime. This tool runtime, it will have a state, okay, short-term memory state, and it will have all these things up as well. Now I hope they make sense.
Mayank: Context is part of runtime, state is separate thing. Context is part of runtime, state is separate thing. State is for short-term memory and everything. Context, by default, you maintain the user ID and all these things up. But yeah, you can just make sure that inside this, you can get all these things up. And state, of course, is having the messages as well, which I told you in the starting.
Mayank: So state is having all these messages as well. Now, if you want, you can pass any information in the state or the context. But yes, this is something which you should be knowing about. I hope this makes sense, everyone. Yes or no?
Mayank: I hope this thing makes sense. So, tool runtime will be got, okay? Tool runtime is having some extra information, and LangChain is sending that. LangChain is saying that whenever you create a tool, your tool will get a tool runtime. It will have all this information of runtime along with some extra things, state, config, tool call ID, all these things will be happening, okay? And this is something which popped up last time, and I think it will be clear as we move forward. So, let's go back to coding.
Mayank: Now I am saying fetch customer preferences. I am able to get context and then get the user ID. So it would not have been possible. Either I need to send it in state or I need to send it in your runtime so that I can access it. Then I could just get preferences. Let's say, as of now, no preferences, everyone. Okay, now focus on coding part. Let me just zoom it in pretty quickly.
Mayank: Then we can just make sure that if runtime, if runtime.store, if there is a store, runtime store, and if memory in the runtime.store.get for this particular user, so I hope you all remember how we used to use this as well, user.
Mayank: and for this user ID. So, I am saying that, hey, if I am having anything in my store for this particular user, then I can set up the preferences. Preferences equals to memory.value, and I could just get the preferences.
Mayank: Now, I really hope you all have revised. I told you that what is the difference between in-memory store and in-memory saver. In the store, how we send this key value pairs, and we are sending this information, everyone. And yeah, this is something which we can use, and we can return the preferences. We can return the preferences. And since this is a store, it can be used across session. So today, if I'm logged into ChatCloud, if I log out and log in, if I open it after 10 days.
Mayank: In the backend, this is how each and everything will be set without you even knowing. So I hope this makes sense that what exactly happened here. I could define another tool. So let me define it up. Functional standby description is not provided. Let me, okay, my bad. So fetch the customers, customers saved preferences.
Mayank: from a long term memory. Yeah, cool. So it is getting initialized. Everyone preference mean any preference which user can have. Now I can have a pref underscore agent create agent. And this is I think where we can copy the code. I can just have an agent like this every month. Pay attention. I'm saying create an agent. It is having the tools.
Mayank: model, tools, context, loyalty store, and everything. And I can maintain, create this agent. Now, with time, I could just change this particular state and all these things, change the same as we move ahead. We can store it inside everything. So that is the whole case. Okay. But this is how you access the same, everyone. This is exactly how you access the same. Anyone has any doubt?
Mayank: Anyone has any doubt?
Mayank: It's not long-term, maybe, right? It's long-term. State is long-term. Sorry, store is long-term. You can have a store which is now based on PostgreSQL. So, that is the case.
Mayank: Clear?
Mayank: Does it also cause if you have long-term memory? It depends. If you're using it with simple SQL, etc, it will not be causing. If it's a very, very good, bigger one, then it will be causing. And it will depend on your memory here, how much memory you are having and everything. Okay, cool. We can make a tool. Let me explain what's cool. We can maintain this tool and use it. Clear?
Mayank: Great. So, what I've done, everyone, in a way, I'm saying that, hey, agent, you can have a store, okay? So, you can have a.
Mayank: DB for long-term preferences in this DB we can save user preferences what are the user preferences just as an example let's say that Mayank Mayank has a user ID Mayank123 and he likes horror and thriller movies okay then let's say there can be Priya with Priya1234.
Mayank: She likes romance and thriller movies. Then there can be one more Priya, but this time her ID is Priya2222. She likes rom-com and horror movie. So now, if required.
Mayank: you can access the same. Rather than you asking user about the user ID, you can just pass it across, and your tool can then access the same and use it. So that is how this whole thing is coming up, everyone. So we are saying that, okay, this is the DB which we have. Now, I am having a runtime. In this runtime, in the context of the runtime, I am sending user ID, user ID.
Mayank: This runtime will be sent to my tool. So let me get the tool icon. This runtime will be sent to my tool along with other information as tool runtime, tool runtime, where I can extract this user ID, where I will get this user ID, get the user ID, and then get this information as well. So I hope now this thing will help you to understand how the circle is getting complete.
Mayank: And this will be a long-term memory, of course. Long-term memory. So, do you think this would have been possible if you don't have this, everyone? Do you think it is possible just with history, with just the conversation history or anything? No, right? You need to have some things via which you can pass these up, and then you can access. So, that is how this thing is coming up without the user even knowing any of these things. Okay, without the user even knowing any of these things. Cool?
Mayank: I hope this thing is clear.
Mayank: Do runtime and tool runtime contain the same information? No, they don't contain the same information. Context can be updated. Yes, it can be updated. Just a minute, everyone. There's a bill. Just give me a minute. Just one minute. Okay, I'm coming.
Mayank: Okay, sorry. Yeah, directly. Can't we get the user info from the client and access it? No, this is how you will be doing it. Very nice, in a nice manner. Okay, you didn't answer other ways of accessing user information other than using the tool and time. What if my model doesn't call any tools, call any tools? It should be fine. No, no, see again.
Mayank: What other ways are there according to you? That is what I'm asking. What other ways are there according to you? What other ways are there according to you?
Mayank: What are the other ways which we will be having? LangChain maintains these things up via which you can access it. No other ways, right? You generally have no other way. So, going back in my runtime.
Mayank: See? So we understood that how this is the runtime, it is having all these things up. Coming to the access, agent can have the context schema, which we have already discussed. Coming to tools, you can access the runtime information inside tools to access the context, read or write long-term memory, write to custom stream, like again, what exactly has happened, give any updates, et cetera.
Mayank: Use the tool runtime parameter to access the runtime object inside a tool. So if your tool needs to get any information, that is what we will be needing, right, everyone? So it should have that runtime where it can maintain these things. LangChain says that, hey, I will be sending this as a tool runtime, which will be having all those five things of runtime and other things as required. Now, many people are saying that we can do user.getUsers. On what will you call .getUsers?
Mayank: So, that is where you're not understanding it, everyone. Pay attention. These are, again, the small, small things. People are saying that we will do .getUsers. On which will you call that? Like, how will you call this up? How will you call this up? Is your tool getting the store, everyone? So, let's say that you are maintaining this long-term memory store with your agent. Is your tool getting the store directly?
Mayank: Is your tool getting the store directly or not? There is no user object, there is no store directly. That is what I want you to understand. That is what I want you to understand. When you define a tool, when you define a tool, LangChain says that, "Hey, I will be passing a tool and type." That is what it is, nothing else.
Mayank: In the tool runtime, Nanjhan is saying that, "Hey, I will have state, I will have five things of runtime, I have tool ID and everything." So, I hope now this is clear. Very subtle thing, very, very subtle thing. Either you pass the user ID in state or you pass it in context. Totally on you, but I hope you're able to understand that what exactly is happening. State is having your messages, everyone. State is having your messages.
Mayank: plus any other thing if custom state. What if tool is not there? Then you will not be getting it. If the tool is not there, then not a problem. If there is no tool, then not an issue.
Mayank: Cool. If the tool is not there, it's not a problem. But if there is a tool, and it needs to access any of these things, this can just be done by doing tool runtime. No other way is there. Cool, everyone?
Mayank: If there is no tool, then it's not a problem. Should not be a problem at all. So, see, tool runtime state, messages, any other thing of custom state. These are having these five things. Runtime is having five, context and everything, context, store, and everything. And yeah, that is how we can use it. So, if your tool needs to access this thing, this is how it does it. That's the whole thing.
Mayank: I hope it is clear, everyone. Many people are thinking that, again, okay, let me ask this question up. Let me ask this question up very, very simply. Let's say that your agent, you create a long-term memory store, okay? So you are defining your agent, and you are storing in your agent this store. If your tool needs to access this store, how will you do that?
Mayank: If your tool, as an example, needs to access this tool, how will you do that?
Mayank: What will you say? That, "Hey, I want to use LoyaltyStore directly." Is this what you say, everyone? LoyaltyStore.get. Is there anyone who is understanding this thing? Is there anyone who is understanding this thing? How will you do that? No, you have to use… LangChain says that, "Hey, I'm giving you runtime. In that runtime, I'm passing everything." That is what you have to use.
Mayank: That is how you have to use that. Let me move forward. I think it will be a little bit more clear. Let me just take another example up, and then I'm pretty sure it will be a lot more clear. Okay, cool. Let's see another thing which we have understood. Have you read about middleware? Have you read about middleware? Yes, in depth. Do you think middleware might require any of these information?
Mayank: Do you think that middleware might require any of this information? I hope all of you remember that we did node style, which was your before model, after model, and all these things. We learned about your wrap style, which was wrap model call. We have seen this.
Mayank: We have seen these two types of middleware, everyone. Now, a simple question. Do you think that, forget about runtime or anything, do you think that tool might need these things? Sorry, middleware might need these things up where it has any information about context. It is able to maintain the store, which is their long-term store and everything. Yes or no?
Mayank: Yes or no? So do you think LangChain as a framework, it should maintain that, hey, I'm passing the, I'm passing this thing so that you can use it. Do you think LangChain as a store, it should be passing these things up so you can use it? So again, now understand, now it will be a lot more clear. First, let's talk about wrap style one, because there is a difference. Wrap, oh, sorry, first the note style, note style hooks. Good. Now pay attention everyone.
Mayank: Let's say this is a function. This is a function log before model. As of now, it's just an empty function. Okay, as of now, it's just an empty function. The second I do before model, it gets transformed into a middleware every month. The second I do before model, yes or no, it gets transformed into a function.
Mayank: And I hope all of you remember. Yes. How many of you remember the error? Something like this error which we were getting when we were trying to create our middleware. So let me show you the error. Let me try to reproduce the error.
Mayank: Something like this. Pay attention. Now see, I am saying that, hey, logged agent, you are a creator agent. Model is, let's say, this model. Okay, I'm not passing any tool to you. I don't need you to have any tool. I want to have this middleware. Okay, let me define this.
Mayank: Okay, let me define this.
Mayank: Cool. So next what we have to do, I think we have to call this as well. Where were we getting the error?
Mayank: Yes, let me call this up. Let's see the error. See, can you tell me what error is there, everyone? Can you tell me what error is there? Read the error properly. It is saying that, hey, logs, log before model, you are not taking anything. I am passing two things. Why are you not taking it? I hope the error is clear, everyone. So.
Mayank: Is your logged agent a LangChain agent? Is your logged agent a LangChain agent? Is your middleware a LangChain middleware? Okay, now LangChain is saying that, Mayank, you have defined this as a middleware. You are passing it to your agent. Now, when you are using this before model, it is not some funny thing that you can write anywhere. When you write it up.
Mayank: Whatever function I'm decorating, this particular function, I send two things here. I can send two things which you need to catch. Okay, what are those two things? Can you see what it is passing everyone? State and runtime. You see this information, state and runtime?
Mayank: Are the things getting connected a little bit now that how your agent gets started with a runtime, that runtime will be required by other components like tools, like middleware. Lang chain has a way of sending it up for tools. Lang chain says that, hey, I will be sending a runtime. Okay, let me define this in a manner. Okay, in this manner as well. So let's copy this tool up. Okay, let's copy this tool up and let's remove this.
Mayank: Let us remove this. I hope that it throws an error as well. Pass. To find it. Okay. Tool. Okay. Function must have a doc string.
Mayank: It should be having a doc string like, hi, I get user preferences. Okay. Let me fix this one for the time being A comma B. Let me define this French customer preferences. Okay. Find this get user.
Mayank: Preferences… let's see, I hope it fails.
Mayank: Okay, so I think with tool, it's a different approach. That is what I was even skeptical about. So let me undo the same because else it will be a problem for you all to understand. Let's define this as it is. Now let's see. Okay, cool. Tool, it can also be shown, but again, for the timing, let's focus on the middleware. I hope you're able to see that Lenk Jain is trying to pass some information and it is saying that, hey, your middleware is not using it. No, it is not catching the same.
Mayank: What are that information and state and runtime? Okay. I hope all of you are able to understand this. Yes or no? So when your model gets defined and when you are using a tool, it passes, it says that, hey, I am passing some information, please catch it. I think tool runtime is actually not a required argument. So that's why it is not failing. When you define a middleware, it says that, hey, I'm passing this thing up. If you want, you can use it. Not a problem.
Mayank: Okay, so pay attention. The second I make it have state and runtime. I can name it anything, but should be fine.
Mayank: I hope you're able to understand it now. Able to understand the same now.
Mayank: Are you able to understand it now? Right, everyone? Okay, so agent is passing state and runtime to our tool. Yes, agent is trying to pass all these things up. Or LangChain, you can say that. Hey, LangChain is passing these things up. Cool. A little bit tricky concept, but important. A little bit tricky, but important. Because as I mentioned, these are not the things which you are directly encoding. This is something which is there. Okay.
Mayank: Cool. Now for people who are still confused about state and runtime, state everyone is having your messages. State is having your messages and any other variable which you want. Runtime is having these five things up. So runtime is having these five things. What are the five things? These five things. Clear?
Mayank: Clear or not?
Mayank: Clear? Can you type AB instead of CHETEN runtime? Yes, it will work. It will surely work.
Mayank: if I type a b it will doesn't care like you should just catch them up nothing else so I can show that as well a b parsing parsing you don't say that hey I'm fine like if you are catching them as a or b I don't I don't care cool so yeah it is working as it is not a problem great so let's let me show you some code it will make a lot of sense now these things because this is something which you got a lot.
Mayank: Last time.
Mayank: It is your custom middle. Now, you will understand that why we were doing it up. Yes. By default, it will not do anything. Note style notes. You see that?
Mayank: Always using state and any node style hook. And then same as the one. Then you are able to access the same as well if you want. Make sense? State dot get. My voice breaking one minute. Is it fine now?
Mayank: Is it fine now? Cool. Now I will explain again. See, when you were using this node style hooks, you'll understand that how it was always getting and using this state and runtime. Let me close the video, actually. Cool. See.
Mayank: I hope now you're able to understand where these things are coming up and what these things are. State is having your previous messages. Messages plus, since it's a custom state, it is having the model called account as well. And runtime is having these five things up. Five things. Make sense? How it is working, everyone? How these things are kind of getting connected? It is not optional. It is being sent. You have to catch them.
Mayank: It is not optional. Okay, cool. For tools, we will check it out. Let me check in front of you so you understand, because again, it is different, different, different frameworks. So, let's see, tools, access context.
Mayank: So… runtime tool runtime.
Mayank: At the rate tool, you can define a normal tool as well, turn type to run time.
Mayank: It can be none as well. So, it is none for the context. My bad. It is optional. Like, you can define a tool normally, and it will not fail. But yes, if you are catching it up, if you want to use it, then you can use the same. It has always been passed, but I think it doesn't show error. Let me check it up. I forget how LangChain handles it, but it should be fine. But yes, if you want, you can use the same app. So, now we have seen everyone. Now it will make a lot of sense again. Let's go back. See this diagram?
Mayank: Tools get or can access the runtime by using the tool runtime parameter. I hope you are clear with this, everyone. Tools can access this runtime using the tool runtime parameter. Okay?
Mayank: Node style hooks directly get the runtime parameter. Node style hooks directly get the runtime parameter. And last is let the wrap style hooks. So let's see the wrap style hooks as well. Let me show you here, but otherwise also it should be very clear. Just that I don't want that you don't understand anything. So that is my idea. See wrap style hooks. Yeah. You see this request, everyone? You see how it is having a request.
Mayank: How many of you are able to see this request?
Mayank: Write model request. Okay. Please increase the font size. It is very much increased. It should be fine.
Mayank: Let me get and show you by going to VS Code Insider, Code Insiders.
Mayank: No.
Mayank: OK, one minute.
Mayank: This is what this is called. Redemption.
Mayank: I think I created a file specifically for this purpose.
Mayank: So, I hope all of you understand that how I am importing them. This is what happens when you import them, right, everyone? When you try to write something up and it gets imported. The reason I'm moving from here, like not on the Google thing. If I click on this, I can see the inbuilt code, everyone. If I click on this, I can see the inbuilt code inside it. And what exactly is defined inside it? Yes or no? If I click on this, see, I'm getting the note. Okay.
Mayank: Do you see how runtime is getting passed here? So, let me quickly help you understand. In wrap-style hooks, so this was for node-style hooks, in wrap-style hooks, okay, you get a request, okay? In wrap-style hooks, when you define a middleware, for example, let's say wrap-model-call.
Mayank: diff let's say I could just have yeah I could have a dynamic prompting thing dynamic greeting prompt okay everyone then again the same thing I can try it out if you want but we know that it will fail so let me first get the imports see for the timing let me do pass.
Mayank: Okay. Wrap model call is 25. Wrap model call.
Mayank: This is the final wrap.
Mayank: Okay, cool. Pay attention. Same thing.
Mayank: If I'm having this agent, wrap style agent, middleware is a wrap style hook. If I call this up, if I call this agent up, let's see if it will throw an error or not. It is saying an error. Dynamic greeting prompt takes zero position argument, but two are given. It is saying that, hey, I was trying to send this request and handler. Why are you not catching it up?
Mayank: If you want your function to be a middleware, you need to cache these things up. Okay, so let me cache it up. Request, which is of type model request, everyone. This request is of type model request and handler. What is the type of handle? Let's see. So, model request, where you can pass the context.
Mayank: schema if you want. Okay, I hope you're able to understand this a little bit. What exactly is happening here? How many of you are able to understand this or not? Like, let me show, like, if you're able to understand, be happy, else I will make you happy. If not, just send us my bad, unsat, sorry, sad face. Sad face if you're not able to understand. Let me understand how many people are there who are not able to understand. Okay.
Mayank: Cool. Neutral. Here. Let me make it a little bit quickly revise. Quickly, let me help you revise. See. You have an agent, everyone. Quick two-minute revision. You have an agent. All clear till now. Can I get a yes?
Mayank: Okay, but yeah, this agent will have a brain. This agent will, of course, have a brain, and then it can have a conversation history as well. Conversation history. This thing, I think, should be clear to each and every one of you. This thing should be clear to each and every one of you. Okay, now LangChain says that, hey, I am, see, this agent will run, so it should have a runtime.
Mayank: This agent will run, so it should have a runtime, like, okay, which, it will have some internal information, which thing it is running on and everything. Plus, this agent will also have a state as well. LangChain is saying that, I'm not saying that. LangChain is saying that. All good till now? All good till now? But LangChain is saying that, hey, your agent, when it runs, see, even when a Python code runs, there is a runtime.
Mayank: This is the complete agent. Lanxin is saying that, hey, you will need to have a runtime. I need to have some information saved for my internal purpose. You should have this ID, some ID associated with it. You should have some information which I need. Please take it up. I hope this makes sense, everyone. I hope this makes sense till now. Now, Lanxin is saying that, Mayank, see, your state, it will be having all these messages.
Mayank: It will be having the messages, all the message history. Complete conversation history. Conversation history. Is this thing clear? You might need this conversation history, right, everyone? You might need this conversation history. Yes or no? Good.
Mayank: Okay, and runtime will have five things. Runtime will have five things. It will have a context, and don't get confused between conversion history and context. It will have context, it will have store, it will have, like this, it will have a few more things as well, like some operator internal, but otherwise, yes, it will be having five things up. Okay, cool, everyone.
Mayank: This is how your agent gets initialized. Now, your agent, everyone, can it have tools and middleware as well? Can it have tools and middleware? Till now, everything is fine. Now, we discussed that how your tool can work a lot better if they can get more context. That I'm not showing you how. We have discussed the same. So, your agent.
Mayank: It is having a tool, everyone. Your agent, it can have middleware as well. Yeah, I think everything is fine. Now, we know that our middleware or our tools, everyone, they can work a lot better if they can get access to some other extra information.
Mayank: If they can get access to some other extra information. Anyone has any doubt till now, anyone who is sad, send me a sad smiley. If you are still sad, send me a sad smiley. Okay, cool. Now, I am also being a little bit…
Mayank: So, I'm also being a little bit opportunist, you can understand, or greedy here. I say to LangChain that LangChain, see, if you are maintaining these things up, I might need to use these things up in future because my tools and my middleware, they can perform a lot better if I'm able to use these things up. So, without.
Mayank: This runtime and everything, everyone, how will your tools and middleware will they access the store? Will you be parsing your store every time? Every time you are getting these tools, will you like to pars this store everywhere? Everyone? Would you like to pars this store? No, right? It is a part of your agent, and your agent should be able to use it up. Okay? Your agent should be able to use this up. Okay? So I am also becoming a little greedy here as a user.
Mayank: And I say to my LangChain that, "LangChain, see, please let me use these things up as and when required." Then it will ask me, "Why do you need these things up?" And I will say to LangChain, "See, LangChain, I explain things in very much depth to my students.
Mayank: Now, you are giving me the code where you are mentioning these things up, and students are not able to understand it, and I need to explain them. Langjet is like, "You are understanding the code, not doing anything from UberUber." And of course, this runtime and everything will be needed for other frameworks as well. So, Langjet says, "Tool mehko, I will pass it as tool runtime." For tool, I will pass it as tool runtime, and it will have.
Mayank: these things. It will have all the things which I showed you, actually. So, let me show you. See, access context. Pay attention, everyone. Lamjan is saying that, hey, man, okay, you're a good fellow. Let me send you all this information. Now, you can use it if required. Not a problem. For me, it's not a problem. You can get this thing up like this. Okay?
Mayank: So, if you want to access these things in tool, totally on you. I am sending you the Context, Host, Team Writer, Execution Info, Server Info, which are the runtime, State, Config, Tool Call ID. You can use these things, not a problem for me. State and runtime. Make sense? Does this make sense, everyone, till now?
Mayank: State store messages. Then, why do you have conversation history separate? Chetal, you have not revised. Conversation history is not separate. It's not a variable. I have just shown it here because it will be there. But somewhere, this conversation history will be maintained. That somewhere is actually state. There is no variable conversation history. There is no variable conversation history. Okay, what does server information contain?
Mayank: Server information. I told you that when it runs on a LangGraph server, that is all these things which it contains. Otherwise, it will be none. Okay, then LangChain said that, okay, all good. Totally on my, totally on me. Okay, totally, totally on me. I am maintaining, I am, I am just using this tool up like this, and you need to explain your student. A middleware, it will depend on the type of middleware. If your middleware is of node style, if your middleware is of node style.
Mayank: Versus, is it of wrap style? Wrap style. I will send based on the type of the middleware. Okay? Okay. I'm not controlling it. Again, LangChain is controlling it. For the node style, everyone, LangChain is saying it, okay, I will send you the state. I will send you the state and runtime so you can use it. Okay? All good? Totally on you. You can use it up like this. Good, everyone?
Mayank: Okay, cool. Now, LangChain is also being a little bit more generous. LangChain is saying that, see, in the state, I maintain messages, history, and everything. This is something which I've shown you again and again, and very, very important. Okay, there's a reason I'm spending time on this because this is pretty much an in-depth thing. See?
Mayank: Every agent manages its execution through AgentState, a type dictionary that holds conversation history and any custom field. So by default, though it is having the messages, LangChain is like MayankC. You are pretty good. If you want, you can extend it and have any other thing which you want, any variable you want, user ID and anything. And in the runtime as well, it is saying that, hey, you can have it in the context as well. So you can extend the context as well and define your anything which you want here should not be a problem. So anything which you want for runtime, you can have it.
Mayank: For state as well, everyone, you can have the same. Okay, so you can have all these things up, which you can use directly. And see, user ID, call count, you can maintain in a particular state, everyone. And in a way, you can maintain them in your runtime context as well. Okay, so totally fine. Just LangChain will say that, hey, just let me know what you are doing. For example.
Mayank: If you say that it is Cinebot state, then just let me know that this time I have to expect Cinebot state, okay? It will be having messages by default, and you can pass any other variable. Very, very similar thing for Context as well. Very, very similar thing for Context as well. Though, ideally, I would need to pass anything which I want during the runtime, okay? Directly to my.
Mayank: Runtime, during the invocation, when the agent gets involved, and in the state as it gets moved forward and everything. For wrap style loop, it is saying that, hey, when you define a wrap style loop, I give you a request. That request is of type model request or tool request, depending on that model request. It will have your runtime and state. It will have your runtime and state so that you can use it up. Cool, everyone? I hope this thing is also clear.
Mayank: I just need these things up runtime. How do you know, Mayank? See?
Mayank: Model request. When there was a model request, which my middleware gets, inside it, I get lots of things. Along with this, I get the runtime and I get the state. Okay? So that is the case in mind. Why are you explaining these things in so much depth? Let's say ADK. Google ADK. Bill agents.
Mayank: Let me search runtime.
Mayank: Agent runtime. See a very similar kind of a thing, everyone. Agent runtime is there. Every other, let's say, framework is following an approach where they're having very similar kind of a thing. So, see, when you go to deployment, agent runtime is there, which can help you in deployment. Like, again, they will be sending some information, etc. So, that is the case. Name will be different, but the concept will be the same.
Mayank: Since we are on LangChain and I want that you understand one thing properly in one framework, it will hold for other things as well. For example, if I go on, let's say CLI, okay, CLI, if let's say we go on its documentation, it will also most probably have something known as runtime or the name might be different streaming runtime contract. If I go on agent, so see agent, agent capabilities.
Mayank: Tools, apps, knowledge. So in some other ways, it will be having it. Role, researcher, tools, MCP. Context capabilities. So it is having knowledge sources, when to use what. I think it is maintaining the same in a knowledge manner. But yeah, that is how basically it gets used. And now you can use this for everyone. So you are getting this up in like this. Now when I define my notes type hook.
Mayank: When I do define my note style hook, sorry, wrap style hook, not note style. Once I define this up like this, you will be able to get it up. Okay, what happened? None type object has no attribute none because we have passed this handler wrongly. This should be something like what they have accessed here, custom middleware. So, wrap style hooks, how is it getting it? Callable.
Mayank: nulls type object if state dictionary message model response dot result so I'm defining the request everyone this is your wrap model call okay wrap model call we are having this and we can return a model response not none I guess right.
Mayank: I am just giving an error because I am doing pass. I should return… I should return it in this manner.
Mayank: Response is handler request. And I could just return it directly. Yeah, should be fine. This put us a, again, little bit of, not advance, just coding, nothing else. Okay. We are just moved away so much of from coding that we need should know that how this happens.
Mayank: Hopefully now it will work.
Mayank: Let's see a real example. Actually, that will make it a lot more helpful. Everyone, let's see a real example. Let's say of dynamic prompting, dynamic, dynamic prompting. We need to pass few things up in our prompt. Everyone, we need to make it personalized. Yes or no? We need to make our prompt personalized. Everyone, I will give break after this concept. Okay, please focus. Please focus.
Mayank: okay so from LangChain we understood this agents middleware I can import a dynamic prompt so this is a middleware everyone I can define it up at the rate dynamic prompt okay prompt sorry my bad Dev personalize the prompt okay.
Mayank: I will get the request. It will have my model request. Now see, this time it's a dynamic prompt. So what I can do again, if you pay attention, like you can go inside this coding or just see the documentation, but you will understand that how it is just having callable returning system message context.
Mayank: agent middleware so it returns you the middleware overall and we can understand that what and everything it extends so we are having personalized the prompt model request now I can do anything okay now pay attention everyone username I can get the name of the user request dot runtime dot context dot say user name.
Mayank: Now, because my model request, it is having the runtime. I know in my runtime, everyone, I am having, those five things up. Context. Okay. All these five things up. I could just use that up and I could just say, return you are Cinebot. Cinebot.
Mayank: Always address user as user_name. Okay, so I have defined a middleware everywhere. Now pay attention. Before my model, before my model, I could define an authorization gate. Okay, I'm defining an authorization gate. Now I get state, which is your agent state.
Mayank: And I get a runtime, which is your runtime. And it can be returned. It overall can return dictionary. Now, how do I remember this? Because I'm spending lots of time. Totally fine if you don't remember the code. Please don't worry. I just remember this because generally I'm spending a lot of time here. Okay, so not an issue at all. Block unauthenticated.
Mayank: created users. Okay, retention. Now, how many of you remember that there was a server info as well in the runtime, everyone? Server info, server-specific metadata when running on LangGraph servers. Then there is anything related to execution, etc. Then, of course, you can have your logic based on any of these things. I could just say.
Mayank: server equals to runtime dot server info. And now I can have any logic based on this thing. But again, the whole idea is very, very simple that you are able to access these things up. Your agent, now it is sending you these things. And now I think the code will be a lot clearer because this runtime and everything pops up at multiple places. Now pretty sure that the code will be a lot clearer.
Mayank: And then, of course, you can just normally define your agent every month. So you can have your agent defined. I can have a complete combined agent, which is having all these things up. So pay attention. If server is not none.
Mayank: then I could raise value error okay an authenticated user any logic which you want that should not be a problem else I can say print if so I could just mention something like auth okay and I could say past.
Mayank: the check for user. Now I can access the user, everyone. This is how I can access the user, right? But in our case, it will be none. In our case, it will be none. Yes, in our case, it will be none. So we will fix it up. It should be none. Then I could get the user from here, everyone. So user can be get via this thing.
Mayank: Right? And… thread ID. Thread ID.
Mayank: 3.30 was…
Mayank: in runtime, execution info, thread ID, okay?
Mayank: So going back, yeah, I think you can define it like this. So it is an execution info, everyone. Execution info dot thread ID. One thing which I would suggest you, whenever we are using any of these things upright, you need to understand that inside them, these are information which we can access. We can easily just go and see. So in runtime, if you will notice everyone.
Mayank: We will be having these things created. So, multiple things are there. In execution info, we are having all these things. Checkpoint, task ID. We will discuss about that in LangChain as well, not a problem. Oh, sorry, LangGraph. But yeah. Now, if you will notice, we can just have it passed, and we should be all good. So, this is also something which I've defined. Name, runtime is not defined. I think I have to get import the same.
Mayank: So, I hope that this is now clear, everyone, that how we can use these things up. This thing, I hope, is clear that how we can use these things up. Anyone has any doubt?
Mayank: We have already seen that how we use store and everything, so that should not be a problem. Let's see. Again, we have seen this example. Just I want to show you how these things are coming up. Earlier, we have already seen that how we can use your… how we can use your…
Mayank: case. What is the practical use of dynamic prompt? Your Cinebot will always know that it has to do anything which you want to pass it up here, right? Anything which you want to pass it up. If there is information which is there in your store, you can access them by using your runtime.
Mayank: If you need to have any other information with respect to user, username, ID, preferences, anything with respect to that, just as an example, a very good example. Now, you will understand how this thing gets done. Whenever I'm passing these instructions, everyone, can you now get that how Claude is sending this up to my AI finally? How many of you are able to understand this, how Claude is setting these things up?
Mayank: So just tell me now, just tell me one thing quickly for people who are still not able to understand. If I define class Claude Context, it can be a data class. Inside this class, I could say user specific instructions. It can be a string. Don't you think that I could do something like this?
Mayank: where above we have all the Claude instructions so Claude instructions okay like I'm taking this up as a variable which we will have not a problem Claude instructions plus I could pass.
Mayank: User-specific instructions. Now, I hope you're able to understand how these things can be passed to everyone, yes or no, how Claude or anything makes sense of this. Dynamically, your prompt can get changed anytime you're doing anything here. Further, how it knows what it needs to call me, Mayank, what is my ID and everything. Plus.
Mayank: Any memory which it is storing, everyone, any memory which it is storing here, any of my preferences, I hope you're able to understand that how it is able to get because it will be stored in a store, right, everyone? It will be stored in a store. This store will be able to access by using the runtime. So are the dots getting connected now? Any authentication, anything which you want to do?
Mayank: Right? So small thing, lots of impact. Because apart from the conversation history, anything which you want to send, these two are the ways through which you can send it up. So now is the runtime state, all these things clear up? Why they're important?
Mayank: Because when we create this DB as well, actually it is also part of your runtime. Like it is actually the store is directly accessible only via runtime only. Like if you create an in-memory store or a PostgreSQL store, okay, you can access them via this only. Cool.
Mayank: When to use state versus runtime? So, state will be used whenever — see, runtime, if you will notice everyone, they will be writing dependency injection for your tools and middleware. Instead of hardcoding values or using global state, you can inject runtime dependencies when invoking your agent.
Mayank: So, in this case, we have to make sure, okay, state and that, let me quickly just see the case. One minute. So, it was mentioned in the state side as well.
Mayank: I remember reading it somewhere. Let me provide that. Okay. I may have to search it up. So let me provide that. But again, everyone, I hope otherwise the approach is clear what exactly happened or what exactly was happening, why we have studied these things in depth. Break, please. Jadhav break. Timer. After break, I will be giving a coupon for big data course. So, timer 10 minutes.
Mayank: Claude, of course, I'm not getting the coupons. When I get it quickly, I will share it, okay? Just wait by next month, so next week, I think. You will have to wait till next month. Coupon gets refreshed every month, yeah?
Mayank: Cool. Good evening. I hope you're able to hear me and see me as well. I was sitting only. Great.
Mayank: Great, great, great. So, few things. Very first thing, DSA course. DSA will open. DSA will try to give tomorrow. First, let me quickly share this to help you revise. Everyone, one thing, if you're liking, if you're understanding that this is very much in depth, please revise. Generally, I don't have any other suggestions. Please, please revise it. It will be much helpful. Coming back.
Mayank: To this, there is a job opportunity which I have added. Please make sure that you go through it. It will be very, very helpful if you are having the relevant experience. But look, again, pay attention. This one is having ITIL 325. Go through the CV ones. Don't just upload it to ChatGPT or Claude and say that, hey, do that. Okay, first thing.
Mayank: this one I think is also the same three to six years you know so that's why I'm saying four the best part it is remote the person is on a little hiding hyper hiding mode so chances are you will get through okay first thing if you're having 20 years of experience I will say not okay that would be helpful shaho second thing if anyone is interested in purchasing the DSA course sorry the other course Claude course you can because.
Mayank: Two things to clear it out because again, this is coming up as a free thing. First, these are not included on your Agentic badge. It's just that we get these coupons up and we share it with everyone. Earlier, Udemy was very good with coupons. It used to give us a lot of coupon.
Mayank: Right now, it is not giving that many coupons. Okay, so I've added a coupon which you can use. It will give you, I think, the best price, which is 399 rupees. Okay, in dollars, I think it's $10. 399 rupees for Indian people. Okay, so if you will go, I think I have already purchased it. So, it is saying 399 for individual course. So, if anyone wants to use that.
Mayank: You can use it. It has also recently became best seller as well, so you can understand. And yeah, good reviews. People are actually understanding. You said you will explain Claude. I'm still saying I will explain Claude. I am not running away from that. I will be explaining you Claude code and everything. It's just that because people are asking and I don't have the coupons. There is a course, everyone. I'm not sure. Okay. How many of you want to study big data? How many of you want to study big data? Have you studied big data or not?
Mayank: Big data is a very good field, like it is one of the best field to get job and money and everything. It talks about Spark, SQL, Spark, Hadoop, Yarn, lots of things. Do you think we should study now? Depends. Normally, 70 to 80% of the job is always data engineering. It is not AI. If it is data engineering, big data is data engineering. So, complete data engineering bootcamp.
Mayank: So if you want, I can share the coupon for this. If you want, I can share the coupon for this. Yeah, I think it will be helpful, but just people who are genuinely want to have it, please just have it rather than completing. Valerie, you can just see this, everyone. So what you can do, just make sure that when you get the access, go to this I and leave a rating. So do leave a very good rating for the course, five star with a good feedback. That would just help us to reach out to other people. Okay.
Mayank: Big data is relevant. Big data is very much relevant. I don't have the one for production one. I can just provide for the courses which I have. Okay. Big data data is same only. Cool. So with that, let me share the coupon everyone. DSA, I will try to get, I have mailed them. I will try to get and share tomorrow.
Mayank: Thank you. Thank you.
Mayank: DSA, let me try it tomorrow. But yeah, please do give a five star rating. Topics khaw promotion khawani karo. Because if you're mentioning to it, it's not promotion bhai. To make a course mil raha hai, khanda khanda kar khawani kar khawani kar khawani kar kar khawani kar khawani kar khawani kar khawani kar khawani kar khawani kar khawani kar khawani.
Mayank: So, thank you for your help. It's great. Thank you everyone. It is not promotion. It is not even in, like, even if I don't give you, it is not going to harm me, right? How will it harm me? These are not freebies. These are just things that because we get, we love to share it with all of you. Nothing else. Okay. It is not anyways from this. So yeah, for people who get this, please do share the feedback.
Mayank: If you have not, just remind me next month. Coupons get refreshed every month, okay? So, I will share the same with you. So, just a little help would be best if you get the access, everyone. See the course. First thing, always see the course. Second, go on AI, leave a rating, give a five-star rating. It will be helpful to reaching out to other people.
Mayank: I won't say it doesn't matter. It is helpful. And otherwise, as well, normally it's pretty good. Okay. And for the job as well, everyone, as I mentioned, I know this person personally. He is asking me to take interviews as well. So I might also take your interviews. So yeah. Okay. Cool. Why Claude Code course not published in Udemy business? It takes a little bit of time. That's why.
Mayank: If the course is good, thankfully, if it's a bestseller, it is a good course. But yes, big data course is very good. Like this is one of the best course, although there are a few things which I have to change. So yes, if there are only 10 coupons to share, please don't share it here. There is around, I think, a hundred people who can get the benefit. So I think it's worth sharing, right, everyone? With a coupon, it was free. If you have not, if you have used it up, then it will not be. Okay.
Mayank: It might get error now because people have taken the same. Cool. No worries. Let me just remind me next month, that is after two weeks, and I will provide you. Yeah, it's 100 of 100. Great, great, great. Let's move forward.
Mayank: Let's move forward. Claude Kupan, I don't have the free one. If you're interested, use the link you will get for 399. Should be fine. Else I will teach Claude code, et cetera. Claude certification and other things will also be updated here. someone from your batch named Ayush is helping me in that. Another, another person, Devyan, she's helping me with the client work. So two people I found very nice in your batch. Okay, great. let's move forward everyone. Let's move to the next concept. Something which is very important, which is going to be your human in the loop.
Mayank: Now, human in the loop, everyone. I think we have already discussed. How many of you remember we discussing this? Human in the loop.
Mayank: Human in the loop. How many of you remember discussing this? Right? We have discussed the pre-built middleware, which ideally is what human in the loop is. Just I want to go in a little bit more in depth so that you are clear with this part. Again, awesome documentation, just making sure that I can demystify documentation for you. It is normally not easy to read, right? How many of you have read documentation in this much depth?
Mayank: How many of you have read documentation in this much depth? Never you will ever read as well. Now, what is the confidence in the concepts of agents? What is the confidence in the concept of agents? I think around 70-80%, you actually know what an agent is, what are all the things. So let's see this awareness. Well, everyone, let us move forward. Shalom. Let's move forward with human in the loop.
Mayank: in depth. Okay. I have kind of already explained to you that how whenever an agent runs FT1, it is running in a loop. So we already know this. Human in the loop. Okay.
Mayank: Let's see. Agent runs in a loop, and ideally, we sit outside it. So, we know that something that is known as Agentic Loop. How many of you are clear with this Agentic Loop? We wrote it down in Python as well. How many of you are aware about that? So, ideally.
Mayank: Terminology is that only, that human in the loop. Agent is running in a loop. It's called an agentic loop. You should be aware about this. I have told that max limit is something which I use. There can be other things as well. When user enters that loop, when you have something which user needs to help with, that is where I think it is most helpful. Going back, everyone, there are actually four things which a user can suggest or mention. Those four things.
Mayank: were something like this.
Mayank: Pay attention. With respect to Synebot, a mini project, I'm explaining all these things. Are we revising it again or something new? No, no, no. There is new, like there is a little bit more in depth so that we can have more conditions and everything. That is something. Revising, though, we will not do as of now. We will do revision in projects majorly. Other projects are revision. Cool. Aja, in this, if you will know, this, you can easily just control here, everyone. So.
Mayank: Please do a research on NBA and provide me the summary. I hope all of you remember that it will ask me the question. This is Claude's way of including me in the loop, right everyone? I hope all of you remember that. Are all these part of MCP? No, no, no, not in MCP. I hope all of you remember it asked the question many times and this question, see, this is now, don't you think this is human in the loop only everyone in a way?
Mayank: Either I could select something, I could mention it as well, and based on that feedback, my agent will learn. So, very, very important concept, something which we should have. I am working on creating a Claude kind of an application, so that is why I'm explaining these things in more depth, because ideally, then we will use these things up, okay? So, for your not major, major project, but for an intermediate project, we can create Claude as well now if you want, okay?
Mayank: So, again, I can just close it up. That is where I've closed it. So, deny. Coming about human in the loop, everyone, we can have a tool. So, let me just quickly have a few things imported. Okay. So, just importing a few of the things up. Now, I am having a tool, everyone, which is cancel booking. It can cancel the booking for me, but I hope you understand the problem with this, right?
Mayank: If I give it a request like this, it will directly go and cancel the booking. And now the problem, everyone, the very first problem, anyone can come up and cancel this booking. So let's say if you are having a booking, everyone, and with the agent, that's a problem. Don't you think anyone can cancel your booking, everyone? Yes or no? If he's using this tool up. Now, don't you think that if someone would have told you how to use this runtime.
Mayank: tool runtime, then you can have an authorization here. You can call some authorization function everywhere. Right? SOMOTH function.
Mayank: So, if authorized, then only you should cancel the booking. In the runtime, you can have all this information. So now, is the real world thing getting clear? Why I explained all these things up? Well, how will you get the user ID and other things? Why runtime only? So, runtime, I hope it is getting connected. Runtime or state, majorly, it will be runtime which will be used. But yeah. So, it's a problem. Like, if you will notice.
Mayank: It's a problem. From rich import print. Print result. See, it might be saying that it has canceled it. See, your booking has been canceled. Like it's a very bad approach, everyone. I think we all know why it's bad.
Mayank: Ideally, the idea should be that it is able to first ask me up. So what I can do, everyone pay attention. Let me define another tool, which will be very, very simple. Booking confirmation. This I think doesn't need my, this overall everyone doesn't need my support. Okay, this is fine. You don't need to have even in the loop here.
Mayank: Now, next thing, which is very, very important, when we talk about human in the loop, I hope you do understand that agent will be imported multiple times, not model. I'm saying agent will be invoked multiple times. Again, I will repeat the statement so that you all understood it. When you invoke your agent, it can connect with your model multiple times. Not a problem.
Mayank: Your model gets invoked multiple times when you invoke your agent, right? Everyone, we all know this, so it can be invoked multiple times. That's all fine. In a single invoke, it remembers everything. In a single invoke, it remembers that everyone, I showed you that, hi, I'm Mayank, and then I asked it again, and it used to forget it. Let me show you it again so that you are very clear with this, because these are the things where people make mistakes.
Mayank: See, hi, I am Mayank. Let me not change it. Actually, let me do it like this.
Mayank: Hi, I am Mayank. Let me answer this. Print result.
Mayank: I hope you do remember that it will not, so now if I ask this, everyone, will it tell me I'm Mayank or not? Will it tell me I am Mayank or not?
Mayank: If anyone feels that Mayank, it will tell you our Mayank revise. Okay? If you remember it, very good, because this is something which sometimes even I face problem, I forget it as well. It is saying, I don't have access to your personal data, so I can't tell you what you are. Let's make a playful guess, summarize who we are from details and everything, right? Now, this is where everyone, we used to use something like in memory saver, in memory saver, right?
Mayank: Memory saver, which used to save the internal memory and everything of my agent. Here we used to have a checkpointing kind of a thing, which we will learn in depth in your, in your, in your, in your, getting this free course is harder than IRCTs in your LangGraph, but we used to have configurable where we used to pass the thread ID.
Mayank: This is the exact thread of which I part. What will be the size of memory depends where it is running. But if you think about it, unless you are loading a lot of multimedia, et cetera, it will not overflow. Plus, actually, I showed you by using a SQL store as well. How many of you remember we used a SQL store? Stored in RAM. Yeah, maybe it's RAM only, no? Okay. So yeah, all these things we have kind of done. I will just quickly paste the code, everyone, so that all of you remember. Pay attention.
Mayank: See, guarded agent, this is something which we decide. ChatGPT 5 mini, cancel booking, send booking confirmation, middleware, human in the loop middleware. We can mention that, hey, cancel the booking or not, and it will listen to you. Now, from where this is coming in, if you go on middleware, human in the loop middleware, it used to have all these configuration options. What were the configuration options?
Mayank: When it should interrupt on, if you are providing nothing, it's all fine. Description prefix, prefix for action request, interrupt on configuration, what are the allowed decision description, and when. So, this when we will also see. Last time, we did not see that. Pay attention. I think this should be very much clear, everyone. Now, I could just provide a config. So, let me provide a config.
Mayank: And I could just invoke my agent, right? I could just easily invoke my agent, so pay attention. See.
Mayank: It is having all these things up. I can't do that. Canceling is reversible. Do you want me to permanently cancel the booking number this? Okay, so it is asking you the question this time, everyone. Is the flow clear? Can I get a smiley face if this is clear till now?
Mayank: Can I get a smiley face? Cool. How do we know, man, that it is asking for human in the loop? Like, how will you tell your UI? How will the UI know that it has not stopped because it wants something, but it has completed the job, or vice versa? Result dot interrupts.
Mayank: if it is there I think okay what was the name of this result guarded agent mock okay print result human message ai message additional kilo k works interrupts submit pass this up.
Mayank: Queues add the middleware to agent middleware list. You configure it with the mapping of tool action to the decision types that are allowed. Okay, I think we missed out on the decision type. Let me check it quickly if we went. So by default, all of them are allowed.
Mayank: Okay, and I think interrupt is empty by default. Just give me a minute, everyone, let me just check quickly.
Mayank: Just I want to make sure that you understand these things up in depth. For the same, let's quickly hit this up. Okay, we saw the result, the normal one.
Mayank: Sorry. Then this time it will remember. This time it will remember it. Tool call did not happen, hence middleware not triggered. No, no, no. Middleware is not related to tool, okay? Middleware is not at all related to tool.
Mayank: Let me check, though I remember last time we discussed this, but should we find result.interrupts?
Mayank: int… reserve it…
Mayank: This object has no attribute interrupts, though it was having it towards the end, right? So let me now call it for cancel booking. Let me make it 2 so that we are all fine. And we'll make it 1-1.
Mayank: So now, again, since the configuration has changed, it will start with a complete new thing. Let me find the results. It is saying that it has been interrupted. So earlier, it was not there, everyone, if you see. Able to see the difference, everyone? And what are the small, small differences?
Mayank: Right?
Mayank: Able to remember it. Now I hope all of you remember there was something which was known as command. I showed you the command as well. How many of you remember? Now you need to command your AI that, hey, what do you want to do? It is not that you can just simply send a yes. You need to command your AI. So if you remember everyone, we used to do something like this. Resumed our result, sorry, guarded dot, sorry, underscore agent.
Mayank: dot invoke. So, I'm invoking it again. I'm invoking my agent again. This is what Claude actually also does. So, when you enter something in here, right, when you enter the thing, you are kind of giving a command and everything, okay? So, it is having these questions and stuff, which we can also have. Now, pay attention. First, I would make sure that I pass the command everywhere. Now, let's see a little bit about, in depth, about this command.
Mayank: There I cannot see the code which you're sending. What should we find?
Mayank: See, okay. There is a resume everyone command where we can send the resume object. It kind of expects a dictionary. Okay. Okay. Let's not go in depth as much. Let's, let me show you the command thing from here. Yeah. See, resume. We are seeing that, Hey, resume.
Mayank: What is the decision we are taking? We are saying that, hey, I'm approving it. So, there are four decisions, everyone, which we discussed. Approve, edit, reject, or respond. Or reject, pass the same config, pass the version as well. If you're maintaining the versioning, pass the same version as well. So, same thing I will do here. I will just pass the command. Let me copy it only because writing it will be difficult. I will pass the command. Okay. So.
Mayank: Let's copy this complete one.
Mayank: So command, then we are saying that resume with the proof. Now it is resumed, everyone. Now if you print resumed, it would have canceled this time. So I can cancel the booking, but this action is irreversible. Do you want me to proceed? Reply yes to confirm and no to keep the booking. So human actually sent cancel booking. Then we said I can cancel the booking and everything.
Mayank: Where is it missing out? Config. Let me quickly check it up. How many of you remember we did the similar kind of a thing when I told you about this thing in depth, right? So same kind of a thing we did a pre one, yes or no? I hope all of you remember this exact same kind of a thing we did where we were then able to make it cancel it. So guarded agent.
Mayank: I'm checking this one. I think we have defined it multiple times, so that is where it might have failed. This was the result as well. So, let me quickly check. Ideally, it should have approved. So, because we have approved, it should have checked. So, that is the case, but let's quickly see what exactly is the problem. Is it thread ID? It can be. Yeah, so let's quickly check it up. Let me.
Mayank: Define my guarded agent again. Let's change it to 111. Config. Then resolve guarded agent.
Mayank: Let's see the result.
Mayank: Okay. So yeah, I think this time it has worked properly. This time we are able to see the interrupt. So yeah, now if you will notice everyone, there is an interrupt value action request. Okay. Yes, yes, yes. So it is now saying, see name, cancel booking, argument, booking ID, description, say about action pending for your approval tool, cancel booking arguments are this review changes, allow decision and approve, edit, reject or respond.
Mayank: So I think we did a mistake earlier. That was why I was thinking that why the interrupts are empty. But I hope you understand now that there is an interrupt. Now I could make sure everyone that I could pass that, hey, I approved the decision. So second part, ideally it will be in a loop, which I will show you in a bit. And now it has been canceled. So I hope this flow is clear now. Since we defined it multiple times, I think that is where it failed the problem. Is this flow clear, everyone? Then what exactly happened here?
Mayank: Is this flow clear? Right now, in a very, very similar fashion, in a very, very similar fashion, everyone, you can do other things as well. I will just paste the other things. So, one is edit. If the arguments are wrong, if the arguments are wrong, why didn't it work earlier? See, what I did was.
Mayank: I… kind of.
Mayank: Oh, one minute. Let me move all this thing up.
Mayank: Oh, hide all output there now.
Mayank: Cool. So, what we did, everyone, was I did a mistake where it was in the wrong state. I did not redefine my agent. I did not redefine my agent. Okay? I did not redefine my agent, and that is why it was having the previous error propagated as well. It was having the previous error propagated as well. Let me quickly help you revise. First, we defined the unguarded agent. It was able to cancel. Everyone was clear till now.
Mayank: When we defined an unguarded agent, it was able to directly cancel. Right, everyone? Then, when we invoked, when we again created this booking confirmation and we had this guarded agent, then we make sure that we are passing human in the loop middleware. Cancel booking. It needs to interrupt.
Mayank: Send booking confirmation. I'm saying that, hey, should be fine. You can send it. Do you think that we need to have human in the loop for this one? Do you think we need to have human in the loop for this one? It's a simple confirmation, not a problem at all. Check pointer in memory saver. It requires a config. Config label. We have a thread ID. We kind of messed the thing here. Now I'm having the guarded agent and it showed me that, hey.
Mayank: I am having a interrupt. It is asking for a request. You can pass either approve, edit, reject, or respond. Result.interrupt, we were able to see that, hey, it is asking for that. And in the next one, everyone, I give it that, hey, my decision is to approve. My decision is to approve. Okay. All good till now.
Mayank: If you're able to understand till now, we have done this actually. We have done this already. So just this part is quick revision. This edit and everything we have not done. This edit and everything is something which we have not done. How can we give decision on runtime and not memory saver? Wrong question. It is not us giving decision on runtime.
Mayank: Sorry, on Memory Saver. Memory Saver is normally being used so that it is getting used up. So, what happened here? Everyone, pay attention. What exactly happened here? In Memory Saver is there so that when I pass my command, it is maintaining that, hey, what all happened previously? It is maintaining that thing up. See, this was the first message, cancel the booking. This was AI message. Then.
Mayank: It asked us for our approval. So, see, AI message and everything, and it asked us for our approval, and we finally canceled the same. So, then booking BK4201 has been canceled. Would you like a confirmation email sent? If so, yes, let me know, and it can send. And see, this time there is no interrupt for anything. Interrupt arises when the agent interrupts its flow and asks you something, or it can be for other cases as well. Clear?
Mayank: What is command? Command is what we send in as an answer to an interrupt. Command is what we send as an answer to an interrupt. Clear? So we are commanding our agent that, hey, this is what you have to do. Agent interrupted the flow for human in the loop. Of course, it needs to interrupt the flow. It is waiting for your command. That is what we send up.
Mayank: Great. We can edit it out if you want to change it up, if by any chance your agent takes a different approach. Now we can reject it as well, everyone. If you want, you can reject the same as well. We will have to define the different configs. Okay, so we have to define the configs separately. We can.
Mayank: require, cancel this as well, cancellation require manager sign off first, ask the customer to call support. Okay? So, let me try to run it, actually.
Mayank: See how it will run.
Mayank: Config 3, configurable, HITEL demo, cancel booking. Let me run this.
Mayank: Can we see, sir, in my Corolla Service portion, it's in my, please discuss if it's relevant. We will have to create a UI for that. Now pay attention, everyone. See, I can't cancel BK10 from here. Cancellation required manager sign off. Please call support so a manager can approve the cancellation. When you contact them, have this ready. Very much how you have an agent, everyone, in real life. When you reject the same.
Mayank: Right? Simple. So, we have covered three. What were the three? Approve, edit, reject, and last one is respond. Last one is respond. Okay? Can you tell your Claude and ask it some question, any clarifying question or anything? When we ask it to run, for example, when we were running it right now for greeting.
Mayank: See, I can mention something else as well here, everyone, right? I can easily mention anything else as well. So that is where response comes in, something which we have not discussed, but since we will be using this in a project as well, so I want to make sure that you understand it. So, again, in this, we will be commanding. Okay, so let me show you the code, everyone, how it will work.
Mayank: Pay attention, see. We can have a tool again. Let's say ask customer. Never actually reach, respond, intercept this. Ask customer a clarifying question and wait for their reply. Okay, so I'm defining this tool up.
Mayank: I'm defining this agent every month. This agent will make a lot of sense as well. It is just having ask customer. Middleware, human in the loop, middleware interrupt on ask customer. Allow decision is just respond this time. Okay, so it will ask the clarifying question. Did we define it up? Check pointer, yeah. Now we can define config. So let me have the config for config ask equals. Let me copy this up.
Mayank: Configurable. Okay. Configurable. Define that. Now I need to just make sure that I can invoke my agent for the very first time. Let me invoke it for the very first time.
Mayank: Today MCP is classes MCP by telling middleware runtime. Again, I hope you joined from the starting. I will start after completing these two things up. So don't worry. These were some important topics before we jump onto MCP. So yes, cool. Let me make it my ask agent first thing. Second, let me make the config underscore ask. So that is what I'm maintaining here.
Mayank: Pretty simple. What is the definition of state and memory saver? We'll come back to that afterwards. Cool. So till now, everyone, I have just a version is you can version your agents if required. Okay. So in the agent part, everyone.
Mayank: Origin. In the agent, if you will see.
Mayank: Let me search. Version.
Mayank: Let me ask from here. Any version is simple versioning the way you are able to give it. Otherwise, I think I told this in the agent part that how it is having a version. So, simple versioning the way you give it. Let the agent run here.
Mayank: Documentation. Yeah, I will explain afterwards. For the timing, just understand it like it's a version. Simple how you maintain a version. If you want, I can remove it as well. Should be fine. If you want, I can remove it. Okay. No problem. No problem. Nothing. Nothing. Not an issue. See, I'm invoking this agent every month. Okay. Don't print the result. Should be fine. You see an interrupt here and how there's an interrupt.
Mayank: Ask customer argument question. Do you want me to cancel booking? If yes, do you prefer a refund? How it is asking the question, everyone? I hope you are able to see that the allowed decision is respond only. Here, the allowed decision is respond, everyone. So, you can respond to your particular request, yes or no.
Mayank: Able to see this?
Mayank: Are you able to see this? Okay, cool. Now what I can do, pay attention. Please show again in a bit slow manner. Everyone, this is a simple, like, this is the same thing which we have done earlier. Hardik, I think I hope you have revised the classes. We have done this thing earlier. I'm just showing you this respond thing, which is new because we didn't discuss respond there. Okay, so this is the same problem, everyone, nothing else. Okay.
Mayank: This is the same problem, not a problem at all. As of now, it is just asking me the clarifying question. Now, on the respond part, I hope all of you understand that we will be invoking my agent again. So, resumed agent respond. I will make sure that I go above and get this part again.
Mayank: what was the name of my agent ask agent ask underscore agent dot invoke this time I will be doing it as respond and I could send it a message okay everyone so I could send it a message it's booking b k 1042 for the movie Interstellar okay.
Mayank: Config should be different as well. Config should be different. Version we can remove because we are not doing any versioning this time, I guess. Yeah, we are not doing any versioning. Should be fine. Okay. And I can invoke it.
Mayank: So, yeah, in a similar fashion, everyone, you can just have this thing up. So, if you will notice, pay attention. Thanks, I can cancel the booking. A couple of quick confirmations. It is asking you more and more questions because it understands that, yes, it can ask these questions up. It is having that Ask Customer tool, which it understands that, hey, via this, I can ask the questions. And yeah, it can keep on asking you questions, similar to how Claude does it here. I hope you're able to understand this, everyone.
Mayank: That how you can respond it in here and based on your response. So this time you're not approving. This time you are not rejecting. This time you're not editing it. You are just chatting with it because every action might not require you to approve, reject, or something. I hope that makes sense. It will never cancel as it doesn't have the tool to cancel. Yeah, it'll never cancel, but it can hallucinate and say that it has been canceled. So not a problem, but yes.
Mayank: So I hope you're able to understand that as a human in the loop, your role is not just to approve, reject, or something. You can play a part where you are being much helpful to your agent as well, which is where Respond is useful. I hope that makes sense, everyone. I hope that does make sense. And normally, it supports multiple as well, so that should not be a problem.
Mayank: Ideally, your UI will play a role here much better than this because your user, it will not write down those commands. Okay? It will not write down those commands. It will have to click on some UI button like Claude gives you that. Okay? You're not taking info from tool. Respond is taking info from human. Yes, human is replying it.
Mayank: Okay, so this time, I have just made sure that I am able to give some input to my agent on which it will not be having anything. It will be just understanding this and working in a collaborative manner. So, not injecting, not approving, not editing — I'm just responding to it with something. Okay, so that is the whole idea, everyone. Cool. So, we have seen the four ways.
Mayank: The major four ways, which are in the loop. Approve, edit, reject, respond. Return the human message directly as synthetic tool result. Skipping execution for ask user style tools. Answer. So let me show you this. I think it will make a lot of sense. Configuring interrupts. Yes.
Mayank: Yeah, yeah. Decision respond, and it can be message blue. And the agent is here, if you will see. Pay attention, this is what we have done. Config, we have defined a config. Result, agent invoke. Okay.
Mayank: Whatever we are asking it, there is an interrupt always because we can see the pro interrupt. We can invoke with the resume and the decision. Okay. One question, we respond the first and then cancel directly. What if he changes his decision? I didn't get the question, Kapil. And you can just now do it like this. So type whatever you are passing it. I think if you don't pass the type, it will give an error or it will just assume something. But yeah.
Mayank: Cool. Now let's move on to the next part, everyone, which is also very good. Do you think that we should always be asked for a cancel thing, or it should be based on some condition?
Mayank: So, conditional interrupts.
Mayank: So, as an example, let's say that you are in a company and you have created an agent, or let's say, for example, in Flipkart, Amazon, and everything. Let's say that you are in an interview. Amazon says that, hey, if the order value is more than 10,000, then it's only when you have to ask the agent, like ask the executive to confirm or deny. I hope this makes a lot of sense.
Mayank: Meet user ask for cancellation, then AI respond. But what if the user again say don't cancel? Will it cancel in that case? If it has not canceled it, then it will not cancel. Then AI will not cancel it. Okay. So I hope that makes sense everyone that how it will be dependent on this. It will be actually dependent on some use case like there is a cancel booking. So what I will do, pay attention.
Mayank: This, I think, will make a lot of simple sense. From LangChainAdian middleware, import tool call request. Cancel booking. Booking ID cancel. Amount is refunded. Now, Swiggy or Amazon interview, you are sitting interview and ask that, hey, we need to make sure that we are having human in the loop based on a condition. How will you have that? How will you have that?
Mayank: How will you have that?
Mayank: Let me explain a little bit. See, custom condition interrupts. We will use that thing, but let's understand a few things about it. User will still give a input which will be very much like cancel my booking ID pk 1011 or something. Can we go through the agentic loop?
Mayank: It will try to understand that, okay, what was the value and everything, get that, okay? And then it will make sure so user can have something like this as well.
Mayank: The value, ideally, it will be getting it from DB, but should be fine. The value was, let's say, 101 USD. Please refund. Okay, so this is how user normally asks. So it will have to make sure it can get this value as well. Then here, instead of a user, like, of course, this user will not be even in the loop this time. This time, we can mention it like Amazon executive exec. Okay, so it will be kind of done on this manner.
Mayank: Now, pay attention, everyone, how we'll be doing it. Pay a lot of attention. Is the problem statement clear? What is the problem statement?
Mayank: Is the problem statement clear? For condition entered, we can create a custom middleware with statement. Ideally, yes, we can do that. Okay. But, LangChain provides that by default. So let's use that. Okay. We need to invoke human in the loop based on a condition. Is it a practical scenario, everyone? Is it a practical problem? Is it a practical problem? Right. So let's see this.
Mayank: Okay, before human in the loop. So, there is nothing like before human in the loop, unfortunately. Before human in the loop. Okay, so see, this is why it is important. Pay attention. First, I will define my function is large different. Now, how many of you remember when we go to tools? And this is where, again, it will be very helpful. Pay attention.
Mayank: whenever we used to call tool everyone we used to have this tool request right tool request what it was exactly tool call request how many of you remember this tool call request so your tool okay your tool whatever it is it used to get that value.
Mayank: Tool call request. Okay, see? When we are wrapping the tool call, in the request, this time it is going as tool call request. In model, what it was, everyone? What it was in model? Model call request.
Mayank: Pay attention.
Mayank: Model request only. Model request. What all will be there in tool call request? Tool call, tool, state, and runtime. I hope the things are getting a little bit clear, a little bit connected. Amihasi, you can check it up if you want. If you want to have a condition based on some amount.
Mayank: You can have that condition based on that amount. If you want to has that condition based on the tool argument, you can have that based on the tool argument. Right, everyone? You need to access these things up during runtime. Okay. Now, if there is some information which is context or state related, you can access it via this. Otherwise, inside this tool call request, I would love to get it here. So.
Mayank: Tool call request is something like this, everyone.
Mayank: Tool call request. In this we cannot see the thing. Now we can, can we?
Mayank: In Kulab, I don't think we can see the same. Could be fine.
Mayank: Okay, so we are having all these things up, everyone. Don't pay attention.
Mayank: See, when the request will go, I think we will be having an amount, everyone. We will be having an amount.
Mayank: right so here it will be tool call request I could say that it is a request and now if you notice it can return a bool okay now I can access it I can guess amount equals whatever request my this tool is getting.
Mayank: cancel booking request okay tool underscore call was present see tool call inside tool call we can get the argument as well the name of the tool and the argument so ideally as of now we are just having a single tool and so you can check the same as well so now notice everyone because it's a little bit tricky the code just to see this I can get the arguments and I could get the amount.
Mayank: And I can say it's zero if it is not present. So, I hope you're able to understand this, that how I'm able to get this everyone. And I can return if amount, let's say, is greater than 100. So, I've defined this function here. I've defined this function here, which takes a tool called request, bool, request, tool called arguments, and I'm getting the amount argument. Anyone has any problem with this piece of code?
Mayank: Any problem in this piece of code? I will now show you where it will get integrated, but first, is there any problem in this piece of code?
Mayank: Cool. Then we can just define our agent. Understand the agent. Conditional agent, create agent. We are providing a model, everyone. Pretty straightforward. We are defining a model here. Pretty straightforward. We are giving it a tool. We are giving it a tool. We are giving it a human in the loop middleware.
Mayank: We are saying that you can interrupt on this function, approve, edit, or reject when we are passing this isLargeDefault function, which we created. So this function which we created, we are passing here. It is not a tool. It is a function which gets this tool called request, and we are having a checkpoint. Now is it getting clear? Now is the dots connecting?
Mayank: Any doubt, anyone know?
Mayank: Pool call request not understanding C. Pay attention.
Mayank: Anyone in the loop?
Mayank: there are other configuration options. See, pay attention. I hope you understand that when, sorry, human in the loop will be called when we are calling some tool, etc. Right, everyone? Human in the loop will be called. See, optional predicate that receives a tool called request and returns true to interrupt or false to auto proof.
Mayank: So, it is saying that, hey, this when it's a callable, which I can call, okay? Whatever callable it will be, it will be receiving this tool call request. I hope you understand what all is there inside tool call request FE1, yes or no, that I showed you.
Mayank: So, LangChain again is kind of saying that, hey, whenever you will define anything here, I can call that, and whatever will be provided here, it will receive this tool call request. Now, this is where you need to understand what all will be there in tool call request. So, via the tool call, I can get what all is there. So, it's kind of like the middleware, and I have had it again. I have had the same via the middleware case, everyone, yes or no?
Mayank: So, let me explain this in a little bit more manner. See, we are having this cancel tool. This agent, it is having HIT and middleware. Middleware. Now, pay attention. We mentioned that when this middleware has to be called, everyone, we mentioned that on which tool it has to be called. So, we kind of mentioned this here.
Mayank: That call the middleware on this tool. By default, it takes all the tool. Now, when this will be called, it will be having some arguments like what is the name of the tool, what is the amount, what is the arguments, sorry, name and the values, booking ID amount, all these things up, right? That is how middleware works. It gets everything. We have seen this already.
Mayank: Middleware, when you have a tool called request and all these things, it is able to catch that up. Now all I'm doing is I'm just again hacking it up. I'm just again hacking it up. So before this gets called, it can generate an interrupt based on the condition. So now if you pay attention, even this is what I'm saying.
Mayank: Open AI GPT 5 mini, everything is there. This when is large refund, it will maintain that what this cancel booking price is getting, the tool call request complete. If it is true, if it is true, then it will interrupt, else it will not. Let me show the practical quickly. Pay attention. See.
Mayank: Pay attention, everyone, in this. Here, the refund is user cancel booking refund $25. Is it greater than 100? Is it greater than 100, everyone? It is not greater than 100, right? Now, the reason I need to make sure that I look human in the loop middleware and not any normal middleware, because then it can ask you the question, it can generate that interrupt. So, see?
Mayank: Config small. Let me push it up.
Mayank: Interrupt. So again, the reason it is giving this error, everyone, because it is not having any interrupt. I think I have to check that. What exactly is the case here? See, no interrupt is there. Nothing here present. Simple. Now, next time when it will be large, pay attention if it will be large this time. This time, I hope you do understand that it will need to interrupt it. So let me see this.
Mayank: Are you able to see that how it is able to pause it? Because if I print r_large, in the end, do you see that it is having an interrupt, everyone? Action request, name, cancel booking price, this description, tool execution requires approval. So, I hope you're able to see the behavior changing, everyone. Yes or no?
Mayank: Are you able to see the behavior changing? It is based on a condition, so your middleware is getting based on a condition, okay?
Mayank: Cool. Makes sense. So, see, this time I have made sure that I'm passing it. Configurable thread ID, large event, I've changed the thread ID. Conditional agent invoke, I'm invoking it with this particular case, and it has paused it. Once it has paused it, everyone, I hope you understand that how it will be. Then, it is totally on us. Now, we have to pass the command. Okay.
Mayank: Before tool call, the middleware is executed. Yes, human in the loop middleware is evaluated and then basically it is called or not based on the condition. Now we are understanding it with the condition here.
Mayank: Okay. Who will improve human user or someone from application dashboard side? It is totally on us now how we are controlling this. Once we get the interrupt, it is totally on us how we are handling it. Okay. But can't we get the same via tool runtime and the messages via tool request? No, we cannot get it via tool runtime. My LangChain is saying that, hey, whatever you are using in this VIN, this VIN thing, whatever you are using here, this VIN, it will get the tool call request.
Mayank: It is saying optional predicate that receives a tool call request and returns true to interrupt or false to auto proof. Just as an example, everyone, now, if you're understanding, if I do return true here and just do like this, now, do you think that it will always be interrupted? It will always be interrupted, right? Because it will, because I'm normally sending true.
Mayank: This is what it is mentioning. This function, it should return true to interrupt or false to auto proof. So yeah, now this time it will always be going forward. Not a problem at all. Everything should be fine. Cheer. Last thing, like to joining all these things up, like exactly how we will be running it. Actually, you know this thing again that has been done with you before. Okay, this has been done with you before, but.
Mayank: Still to quickly advise you, this code I have already given you before as well. If you remember, this was the kind of a code, everyone, which we had. Run interactive HITL. We used to invoke the agent. If there are no interrupts, we used to return. If there were interrupts, then we used to ask it what human wants to do. Right, everyone? So let me run this, and this will get clear. See?
Mayank: This is how you can control things in the UI. This is a very simple case. I hope you're able to understand. So this time it is running in a loop like Claude runs. This is how Claude kind of does that with a good UI adjust. Right or wrong, everyone?
Mayank: This is how Claude handles it. Pay attention. The code, this code I've already given you. That is why I'm just making it quicker.
Mayank: Okay, so I will quickly help you understand the code. We are still doing the same thing. We are just checking if interrupts are there, printing these things up. We are asking users for the input. It will keep on waiting for the input, no timeout, nothing we have added. But this time, when users select one, two, or three, we just take the case and we create our own command. So see decision.
Mayank: and we pass this up as a command. This is how you will be handling it. The user will not be writing those commands and everything. You will be making sure that you handle it inside your code. So now I can approve it, I could cancel it, and everything. Clear, everyone?
Mayank: If anyone has any doubt now, HITL, I think it is clear a lot. This is how Claude also uses it, ChatGPT, every other framework, every other Agentic website or something are using it like this. And yeah, this is the level of in-depth which HITL might be required. This is at the highest level of HITL. Now, why this much in-depth? Again, the same cheese, new AI docs.
Mayank: Clear documentation, documentation, human in the loop, human input on execution and human in the loop workflows. Flow based, web book based, same thing, configure task, human input to Dhaldhya. Yeah, it will ask you the same thing, but concept is same. Practices will be a little different, but concept and everything will be the same. So human feedback in flows, this is the other case. Human input on execution. Okay.
Mayank: So all the cases, they just make it pretty much in the similar side. Nothing else. Yeah. Feedback, human feedback result, it will understand what is happening. It is not difficult. It is generally easy. Just that concept of a clear, okay, it is more than simple thing. So now I can do that. Hey, edit it out.
Mayank: See, it is asking me. Booking ID to cancel instead. I could say, hey, I checked it, I am a case, 10011.
Mayank: Okay, I think we have to showcase the final result. So, this code you can just make sure that you correct it. So, this time it is saying done booking BK funds has been cancelled. Email sent BK 1042. What did I provide? I think we have to check it like maybe something we have to fix it up here should be fine. Let me just show you the one.
Mayank: Is there two of my follower? One minute.
Mayank: But anyways, yeah, this you can fix up. Should not be a problem. I could just approve it here and then it will say done. The booking has been canceled. Would you like to have a canceled booking? Ideally, again, we can configure that it has to send an interrupt here as well, but that I think we can control quickly. But yeah, this is how the loop works, everyone. This is very complex. No, it is not. I have almost revised you what you all knew. Otherwise, it was all.
Mayank: Just these two, three things were extra, like the conditional one and the feedback one, nothing else. Okay, great. So with that, everyone, you have lots of things to revise. How many of you have never, don't know what MCP is? How many of you don't know what MCP is?
Mayank: If you don't know MCP, no, nothing. MCP will teach in very much depth. It will be very, very much in depth. So do you want to create your own MCP servers which you can connect with Claude, which you can use, give to anyone, to your friend? Do you want to have that level of knowledge? Because we will be doing it at that level. Okay, so just letting you know beforehand, now you have a very good time to revise LangChain.
Mayank: kyu ki before I move to Multi Agent, MCP will be done in very much in-depth. Kyu kyu kyu? MCP will be done in very much in-depth. I'm letting you know it will be taking at least 3 classes, at least.
Mayank: But once you do MCP in depth, you will be able to create your own MCP servers. You will actually be able to understand why it fails, why it doesn't. You will understand at a level of Amazon Google companies that, hey, what level of in-depth knowledge is required in MCP? What are the different, different things? So do remember these now. Okay? Pre-request for MCP, nothing. Nothing. Little bit of fast API, maybe else nothing. Okay?
Mayank: Cool. So this is where everyone, we are pausing our land chain a little bit because we will continue with MCP tomorrow. And MCP, once we cover it, we will then see that, okay, what are all these things? So transport, HTTP, passing headers, authentication, STDIU, what are all these things? We will understand it very much in depth. What are these resources, these prompts? These are very much, so I have actually done the groundwork. So that's why I'm telling you, I have done it way earlier.
Mayank: So it will very much and times do. So that is something which you have to understand. Okay, great. So now let me do quickly few things up runtime and runtime and HITL. One more thing everyone, let me show you that one more thing quickly noticed.
Mayank: When I share the file with you all, when I share the file with you all, many of you might not see some images. Many of you might not see some images. This person is from Excalidraw team. He's saying that export is having some trouble with WebP images. So you might see some images, some not. So they are fixing it. I reach out to Excalidraw. Cool. So when I do export here.
Mayank: When I do runtime plus HITL and when I will do an export from here, pay attention, quick export PDF.
Mayank: images will not load. Okay, so just letting you know that this is not at my issues. So that is why I've started sharing the Excalidraw file as well directly. So I'm sharing the Excalidraw file as well so that you can open that as well. Save. It might not have some images. Pay attention. See, it ate up that agent here.
Mayank: You know, so that is the case. So cool. With that, I think we are done. Let me just upload everything on your class here. So today it's class. GitHub I will upload. Apparently it should not be a problem. Let me quickly get this as well. Download, download, download.
Mayank: And also have your VS code ready because, MCP, we will not be doing it here. Okay? So MCP, we will be doing it, this. So now if you refresh everyone, I think this is having a very good thing. Wait, is it 20 seconds? Yeah. So yes, I think we are at a good speed and everything should not be a problem. Let's now just start with MCP. MCP should be fine. Cool.
Mayank: Let me allow you to raise hand.
Mayank: Cool. Now you can raise hand, everyone. Again, just a humble request. Please send me the CVs before tomorrow. I will be sending this on Monday for sure. I will not be making it late. Please revise if you're having any issues. And yeah, you can ask me the doubts. And if you have sent me the email, you will be getting the reply this week. I was a lot occupied in multiple things. So that is the case. But again, a very depth me hatchi se. To MCP toward masai hai, yaar pashkil hai. But let's see.
Mayank: By October, do you think you will be ready to give interviews? Yes, by October, easily. We will be easily, a lot easily. You will have done LangChain in depth, LangGraph half as well. So, kho jayega matlab, should not be a problem. For sure, you will be able to do because we will be doing two projects as well by that time. Cloud-based project, for sure.
Chouki Bhanu Prasad: Hey, yeah. Hi, man. Bano here.
Mayank: Yes, ma'am, yeah.
Chouki Bhanu Prasad: Yeah, so in the assessment you have given, so our agent have three different kinds of tools, and we also need to give the response format as well, right?
Mayank: No.
Chouki Bhanu Prasad: Response.
Mayank: You're asking about the assignment?
Chouki Bhanu Prasad: Yes, yes.
Mayank: One minute, let me open it. I have time at Agent 2, Part A1 Conceptual Questions, Coding Exercises. Which one exactly?
Chouki Bhanu Prasad: Capstone toilet.
Mayank: I created this. Built a single key agent for Nova Bank, combining at least six of the following.
Chouki Bhanu Prasad: You know.
Mayank: response format scheme of a structured banking request with at least one real constraint. Hmm.
Chouki Bhanu Prasad: So my question is, if I give three tools to the agent, and if I give the response format to the agent, the agent can, like, answer always, all the time, with the response structure only. If I greet the agent, like, hi, it cannot greeting me like human. It is always giving in the response format. So…
Mayank: But that's not a problem. We are using that by default. Like we are using the structure output.
Chouki Bhanu Prasad: Yes, but for the final answer summarization, after implementing all the tools, how it can give us the answer in human format, because it should be able to give all the time in the…
Mayank: Maybe, but if you're using a tool, if you're using LLM, LLM gives you the answer on top of that. There was a direct, I remember there was something known as direct, which you can use to give directly the structured output, else it used to summarize the same.
Chouki Bhanu Prasad: Actually, I have implemented this response format all the time, it is giving in that one only. Not even talking, like, human.
Mayank: Then it should, it should, are you sure you have not, like, again, if you have asked Chad, GPT, or Claude to create the code for you, I hope you have not. You have seen that there's a direct thing, which I…
Chouki Bhanu Prasad: Yeah, you mean the written directly.
Mayank: Monitor direct something like, yeah.
Chouki Bhanu Prasad: Yes, the tool can return the answer, but the agent final summarization, how it can do, because we have given responsible.
Mayank: Which model you are using?
Chouki Bhanu Prasad: I've given… I'm using GPT-5 mini something.
Mayank: Return direct is true, you were saying, or it is false.
Chouki Bhanu Prasad: For… for tool, it's up to us. I mean, agent… agent is.
Mayank: In the tool, what you're using it. If you use it as true, then it doesn't go through the LLM, right? It just gives you the.
Chouki Bhanu Prasad: Like, my question is, after implementing all the tools, the agent should summarize the information and give us the answer.
Mayank: It should be doing that, I'm asking you that. It should be doing that by default. If it isn't.
Chouki Bhanu Prasad: Okay, then I'll… I'll try.
Mayank: Oh.
Chouki Bhanu Prasad: the model. Maybe a model.
Mayank: to either change the model or just check if return direct is not set as true by default.
Chouki Bhanu Prasad: Okay.
Mayank: Okay, so it should give it like otherwise, if even if it gives you the structure output, it should give it either you have to change the model if it is some very mini one, okay, or nano one, or just check once that if you have asked AI to write the code, it has not given you the code in terms of where it is true by any chance you missed out, maybe, or maybe it has set.
Chouki Bhanu Prasad: I use, like, hands-on coding.
Mayank: Fantastic.
Chouki Bhanu Prasad: Only one thing, Mayank. So, my agent, if I give response format, and I have given one tool, so I've given a question which is not related to tool, LLM knowledge, it can answer me. So, how it can respond? It can respond in response format, or normally, like, human?
Mayank: It depends. It depends. Again, I think you're getting confused. If your agent is having a response format, for example.
Mayank: These are two things here, no?
Mayank: If your agent is having the structured output, then it agent would always try to give it in that manner. So if you want agents, there is a structured output. If you provide that for your agent, then agent would always give it like this. Okay. Second is tool. Tools also have that, right? So if, if you are removing this structure, this one, one minute. Yeah.
Mayank: Yeah, this response format, if you're using this, then agent will always give it in a response format, whatever you are passing it here. That is one thing. Second, it calls the tool. Tools return it in some format. If you want, you can use pydantic, et cetera, with tool as well. On top of that, it applies the LLM. If you are passing return directly, then it will not apply the LLM. So.
Mayank: I think you're using response format, then it will always give that, should not be a problem.
Chouki Bhanu Prasad: Okay, after giving the tool results, the final response, what the LLM can reply, Mayank?
Mayank: After giving the?
Chouki Bhanu Prasad: tool response to the LLM? What final response we'll get? In response format only, or not?
Mayank: In response format. LLM will understand that he… the agent response should be in the response format. That is how it works.
Chouki Bhanu Prasad: All the time.
Mayank: It will try. If your model is good, it will try to fix it all the time.
Chouki Bhanu Prasad: Okay.
Mayank: Every time, rather. Not all the time, every time.
Chouki Bhanu Prasad: Okay, okay, thank you, Mike. Thank you so much.
Mayank: Cool. But I hope the assignment is pretty good, everyone, because I've included lots of questions. You will get the solution by the next class.
Mayank: Next week.
Chouki Bhanu Prasad: Yes, but in that one, we have one more thing, like tool error and tool retry. Even if you're implementing in different order, first tool error and tool retry, it is doing the same thing, just calling tool multiple times.
Mayank: It depends, right? I've given you the middleware. So, it will retry the tool when it fails only. Otherwise, it will not retry it. I discussed these things up. Same for tool error. It can catch the exception and return you the error in a much better manner. So, what will happen here? Tool retry will take the precedence over tool error. If there is an error, first, it will try to retry it.
Mayank: If after maximum 3 retries it fails, then it will give you the tool error. So that is how it should work, right?
Chouki Bhanu Prasad: Yes.
Mayank: So it should be the case. That is how you will understand that, yeah, this is what is happening.
Chouki Bhanu Prasad: Yeah, what happened in… we implemented in alternate, like, first a tool error, then tool retry?
Mayank: It doesn't matter. I think it will be still, it'll try to do the same because tool retries internal tool error is afterwards when it is returned. So it'll still try to run it multiple times, then it'll finally return the error to you.
Chouki Bhanu Prasad: Okay.
Mayank: Tool retry will take the precedence like tool retry is going to be around middle. So I hope you remember that when I told you the order of executions, right? Execution order when we are having multiple ones.
Chouki Bhanu Prasad: Yes.
Mayank: If you think about this, tool error will get called when finally there's an error, but tool retry will always be earlier than that. So it will try to have a maximum retries of three, and then it will give you that error.
Chouki Bhanu Prasad: Yes, actually, I implemented in alternate ways. First, I tried with tool error, like, tool retry with two times, and then I implemented tool error, then it working fine. And alternate, then I tried next time, first tool error, then tool retry. It is looping more times.
Mayank: Let me check it up. Like, again, they keep on changing this. Ideally, the approach should be that we should have two retry first and two later next, so that we are retrying it, and if still the error is coming, then we are handling it better.
Chouki Bhanu Prasad: Yes, yes, instead of looping again and again.
Mayank: Exactly. If you're passing tool error first, then what can happen is that it might, whenever there is an error, so whenever there is an error, it might give you the, like how you have handled the error. So it might do it number of retry site type, but that's a wrong way. Like if you're doing it like this, ideally you should have tool retry and then tool error.
Chouki Bhanu Prasad: Yeah, just for experimenting, I'm checking.
Mayank: Maybe it's a good thing, it's a guy I always appreciate, ki understand by experimenting, break the code.
Chouki Bhanu Prasad: But could you tell me how to track what's happening inside, how it is calling? Can we do that?
Mayank: Oh, you can see the complete, complete, complete diagrams, which are the way I've shown you the complete, stack trace of everything. If you will see the result and everything, it will be able to showcase that, right? I have always shown you by doing just good from rich import print, and then just make sure that you're doing it like this. So you can see everything. Just see this thing. If you're not seeing this, then it's also a problem.
Chouki Bhanu Prasad: Okay.
Mayank: Okay.
Chouki Bhanu Prasad: Yeah, thanks, Mike.
Mayank: Good, thank you.
dipika vijapur: Hello, hi, Mayank. Good afternoon… good morning. So, I just.
Mayank: I had to go.
dipika vijapur: one question. So, I just was going through the job description that you posted.
dipika vijapur: There are many of the things that I do not know, and we have not covered, only few things which we work regularly.
Mayank: 60% you can apply.
dipika vijapur: Okay.
Mayank: the final person taking the call for the interim CVs, which will be going forward, along with one more person.
Mayank: The best thing is that, see, I know the person personally. We are working on some projects. He's having an agency that is for which he's hiring it.
dipika vijapur: Mmhm.
Mayank: So…
Mayank: I will see if it is valid. If you know 50 to 60%, you should find. If you know less than 50%, then don't. If the experience is in the range of 5 to 8 years, and salary is fine, then you can apply as well.
dipika vijapur: Okay.
Mayank: Okay, so that is the case. Just that two sent me your CV by proper CV.
Mayank: by Sunday, that is by tomorrow, because on Monday, I will be forwarding it for sure.
dipika vijapur: Okay. And the second question is, Mayank, like you shared for Python, right, do you have any, topic-wise YouTube channel for all this that you're covering? Because some topic, we don't want to go through the whole session, then we want to, just check few topics like that, so you have any YouTube channel of yours, like…
Mayank: I have a YouTube channel, but I have not taught LangChain there.
dipika vijapur: Okay.
Mayank: I'm teaching, by the way, I've taught it multiple times, but not on my YouTube. I will be doing that, because for your batch, I'm teaching it very much in depth.
dipika vijapur: Yeah, you'.
Mayank: Yeah. So we do that and let you know, okay.
dipika vijapur: Yeah, yeah, sure. Thank you. Thank you.
Debajyoti Mukhopadhyay: Hi, Mike.
Nitin Gupta: I'm fine, Nathani.
Mayank: One minute. You said it.
Nitin Gupta: Okay. Mike, I have a question related to this kind of generic question, okay? Like, we are learning now, currently, how to create agent using LangChain, right?
Nitin Gupta: And there are a lot of libraries I see inside, which is helpful. But I just want to know, understand the difference, like when we should use LangGraph and when we should use LangChain and why?
Mayank: So, ideally, when we will cover LangGraph, it will be a little bit more clear. See, when you don't want to control in depth of as a graph inside your execution, when you want to, when you are fine with this level of thing, which we are able to do, right? LangGraph is fine. Sorry, LangChain is fine. LangGraph gives you much more control over this state and everything so that when there is a complex requirement.
Mayank: When you want to make sure that you are actually having a lot more control, okay, that is where LangGraph will be used. Once we study LangGraph and you see its feature, then you will be able to take up that call that, okay, this is where LangGraph should be used. But ideally, when we want to go into the level, because just to show you, if we are having any agent, right? What was the agent we are having?
Mayank: Let's say this one, conditional agent. Ideally, when we define this agent in the backend, a LangGraph code is getting created. And via that LangGraph code, something like this is getting created. LangGraph helps you to control it, make any changes manually, because here, this graph is getting created itself, right?
Mayank: Via LangGraph, we can control this graph a lot more in depth. We can actually pass that, okay, I want it before it. I want to do any tool call before this as well, before even my model gets up. You can do all those things as well a lot better because LangGraph will define the graph from scratch.
Nitin Gupta: Yeah, because what I understood LangGraph is basically when we want to make a complex agentic flow, then LangGraph is actually better.
Mayank: I agree, yes, when you want to define a lot more in depth one, but again, it depends. Many people will teach LangGraph just from top and not in depth, but we will be seeing that in depth as well. LangGraph is very much, again.
Nitin Gupta: And how AI AutoGen helps?
Mayank: AutoGen is another framework by which you can define the agents and everything. Exactly the same thing in there as well, just that it is having some different things. I think I will not be covering AutoGen because it is not used a lot. I will give you the recording, but again, the same thing. See, you can define models, messages, agents. AutoGen directly allows you to define team as well, which is your multi-agent architecture, and you just define in the same manner what you want.
Mayank: Then it is also having the state, saving and loading agents, maintaining the state and everything, human in the loop. So very, very similar things, nothing very major, just that it is taking a different approach of doing the same thing, nothing else.
Mayank: Yep.
Nitin Gupta: Okay, okay. So in this Agentic flow, like when, I mean, when we, I mean, we saw in the class today also, like in Nigeria, we are calling tools, right? So this tool calling is something similar, like what we call MCP Sukrasa, right?
Mayank: Kind of, yes. Kind of.
Nitin Gupta: Right, because if we go from a LangChain perspective, then we have this option, like, create our tools and make calls. And when we go through, let's say, Cursor point of view, then probably we need MCP as a replacement of tools.
Mayank: In next two through three classes, your LangChain will also be able to call MCP.
Nitin Gupta: Langchain will also be able to… okay, yeah, you showed that there is a module of calling MCP.
Mayank: Hu.
Nitin Gupta: But that is kind of a same thing, right? It's a tool only.
Nitin Gupta: Also, we used to call a tool, correct?
Mayank: Yes, MCP in a very simple sense is collection of tools.
Mayank: I was a bit confused, like, you know, like, why we need tools, like, why we need this. So, I just want to understand the difference. So, that's why I was asking this. So, to me, it looks like a similar thing. Oh, it is similar. You see?
Nitin Gupta: The thing is, now I see everything is, like, you know, I was a bit confused, like, you know, like, why we need tools, like, why we need this, so I just want to understand the difference, so that's why I was asking this. So, to me, it looks like the similar thing.
Mayank: Oh, it is similar. It is. See, every of these concepts, the reason I'm again focusing a lot on concept is that only they, once you understand that in depth, they are more or less similar. This is nothing which is difficult or something. So they are more or less similar.
Mayank: So that is the reason in AutoGen or any other framework, the concept is the same. You will see that all these concepts are something which I've kind of explained to you. Human-in-the-loop, teams, agents, messages, models, state management. Okay, then memory, RAG, all these things we will learn. It is also having this graph flow where you can create a graph from scratch. But yeah, almost the same thing.
Mayank: Just it is on us and I feel that it is just totally understood that let's focus on concept because once you understand the concept, then you will be able to read it and yourself also do these things. Okay.
Nitin Gupta: Okay. Oh, thank you, Mike.
Mayank: I think once, yeah, once we do the questions, I think it'll be much more clear for your project. In a single project, I think it'll get clear, so it should be fine.
Nitin Gupta: Approximately when we're going to do the project.
Nitin Gupta: MCP ID.
Mayank: I think I will be doing the project, so it will be around two next weeks. I think by next week, I will be completing project. Oh, sorry, MCP.
Nitin Gupta: Then.
Mayank: Oh.
Nitin Gupta: Who's.
Mayank: Yeah, let me just see. Let me quickly just tell you, like, I just want to, but I think, yeah, there will be no best time for project. So let me see this. We are having agents we have defined via AP five. I define kia fetch actual tokens, config schema project. I just have to see. So this is the reason I'm telling you MCP because we will be creating an MCP server here.
Mayank: Why this list tools is there called tools? So that I can explain all of you, that is the reason I want to teach in depth.
Nitin Gupta: I think I'll find for that one for check. Well, ports have APASAP, so I think.
Mayank: I will be teaching in this depth only, in this class only.
Nitin Gupta: It's a few projects and I'm.
Mayank: We'll have the cleaner ticket should be.
Mayank: Madhav projects niljanjay ki hai.
Nitin Gupta: It's a good.
Mayank: So, projects to bot sari hai, yaar piiranan agent spas bhai nahi hai nahi hai nahi hai nahi hai nahi hai nahi hai nahi hai
Debajyoti Mukhopadhyay: Yeah, hi, Mike. Yes, hi, David.
Nitin Gupta: Bye.
Debajyoti Mukhopadhyay: Hello. Two, three questions. Probably one.
Mayank: No, no, we need to m.
Debajyoti Mukhopadhyay: Yeah. So, Palajijai ki, you've shown the ADK, right? And in our project also, ADK use Utha. So, ADK and Langchain, as per the concept, or ADK with Langarav, is not much difference, only the functions and, and, maybe the syntaxes are, kind of different, but conceptually both are same, right? Udono ya ki type, right?
Mayank: Haan, madam, don't help you to get agents. Abhijit, if you have agents, you can use them.
Debajyoti Mukhopadhyay: Pacha, okay.
Mayank: Multi-agent toga, simple agent toga, yoga agent toga jyoti find kar.
Mayank: Exactly same. Human in the loop. Graph workflows. Graph analytics. Land graphs. Models are there. So, models are there. So, if you look at it, you will see that there is a lot of time left. You will see that there is a lot of time left.
Debajyoti Mukhopadhyay: Correct. But once it's clear, then any framework, Jyobi framework…
Mayank: I will keep you like a crash course. I will teach you in a two class I will take to teach. Two class I will teach, take to quickly do a project. So work proof checking concept, project, concept, project. Once the concepts are already properly clear.
Debajyoti Mukhopadhyay: 80k you will touch, right? U.
Mayank: I believe in the title.
Debajyoti Mukhopadhyay: core question, jabi bhi m multi-agentic system ka baatkar, the multi-agent flow, right? So, usme hum ka Landgrafi use hot.
Mayank: I will be teaching you. I have the resources created. I have only seen the resources created as of now as well. So, it's a multi agent. Okay. Sub agent, handoff, skills, router, etc.
Debajyoti Mukhopadhyay: Okay. Last question. Jabi hum, memory kabat karthik, right? Agentic memory, memory optimizations and all. Right? Usme hameshar rags use hota in the real time project or yafir, jaise hamne database ket ruby load kya or usko langchen ket through read kya. So that also works. I mean, mainly in production grid project, right, kase memory.
Mayank: Depends. We understand the real use case. Memory we use is RAG. Documents we use is RAG.
Debajyoti Mukhopadhyay: Okay.
Mayank: aapiya mahar bhas matlab, pata hai ki pause saara data hosko memory mini saif kara sakte hai. Memory saif kara sakte hai. Memory saif kara jaan bhi kya find a structure, we know kya kchais thari ki sais ko saif khanda hai, kuch structure bhat sakta hai. Chitna kaam se ka mahara mein hai, hota hai kya hai kya kya kya ka.
Debajyoti Mukhopadhyay: Okay, yeah.
Debajyoti Mukhopadhyay: Got it. Thank you.
Mayank: Okay, the major.
Jayanth: Okay.
Mayank: Dimensions.
Debanjan Mani_Laptop: So…
Mayank: Yes, I mean that.
Debanjan Mani_Laptop: Yeah, hi, Brian. So the thing is, well, I'm, lagging, quite a few classes, Brian, like, 5, 6 classes, and I'm still going through the initial land chain,
Debanjan Mani_Laptop: Sessions.
Debanjan Mani_Laptop: So, the thing is, I'm, I'm, I'm able to, run the, the, the, like land chain portion experiment on, full lab, but,
Debanjan Mani_Laptop: When I'm trying to do that on VS Code, I'm getting some strange errors, so I'm not able to solve those by message. Can I show that?
Mayank: Can you ping me that once? Just ping me, I will tell you. Like, it should be some library-related error. We are not doing anything on the Pollab, like, just simple.
Debanjan Mani_Laptop: This, okay,
Mayank: You can just ping once, else I will give you the waiters.
Mayank: Okay, cool. Tenth.
Jayanth: Hi, Mank. Remember a couple of weeks ago, I asked about, a new agent application.
Mayank: Which one?
Jayanth: You might not remember it. A couple of weeks ago, I had an idea of building a, say, Agentica News AI.
Jayanth: I actually finished building it. Here is the link. If you want to give it a try, can you give it a try?
Mayank: Sure.
Jayanth: It's already deploy.
Mayank: I don't remember it.
Mayank: Yes, those things.
Jayanth: It's deployed on US servers, so it might have some delay.
Mayank: It's.
Mayank: Explained.
Jayanth: Yeah. You can chat with it, it's voice enabled, you can talk to it, and it can talk to you back.
Mayank: Nini is looking pretty good. Like the UI and everything is pretty good. So this thing is also fine powered by CH. This is where we can chat with it. It will get all the information.
Jayanth: Yes.
Mayank: Text, right? What all you have used in here?
Jayanth: For the deployment, it's entirely on, AWS, ECS and Fargate, that kind of deployment. For the agent, on the background agents, it's LangGraph.
Mayank: Okay.
Jayanth: And, there are a lot more things. If you want, I will share you the GitHub link.
Mayank: Oh, just share it with me. I will go through it. And if, you are fine with it, we can teach it in the class as well. Yeah, overall, I think it will be helpful. Although I have projects on LangGraph already, but yeah, we can create it quickly. We can have, create an MCP for this as well, if required. This will be helpful.
Jayanth: Yeah, it's RAG based completely.
Jayanth: Whatever that's coming in, it's going to my PostgreSQL on AWS.
Mayank: PostgreSQL and you have managed to ta.
Jayanth: It on. Yes.
Mayank: Why have you created a RAG, but, like, don't you think it will be very quickly updated and all these things, so…
Jayanth: Italy, I.
Mayank: How many news are we getting? How many news articles are we getting here?
Jayanth: Actually, there is a… there is a limitation here, because the news APIs, right? So…
Jayanth: I can only call… then I can only make a few calls a day.
Mayank: Mmhm.
Jayanth: So, that's why I'm prioritizing some things, and whatever I am getting it, so I am storing in my database. And what you are seeing is not a full article. No.
Jayanth: Whenever you click on something, what you get is a summary.
Mayank: Okay.
Jayanth: You can ask regarding the summary, and I have already attached Tavli to this, so you can do web search as well.
Mayank: Yeah, that makes sense. Just, I think I will do one good thing here, like, because you're already sharing it in the DB and everything, right?
Mayank: Just try to see how you can reduce the RAG dependency because RAG, you will be storing it and over time this will get, still charge you money and it will be kind of not that worth it. So I think either you should have a TTL on RAG, let's say by seven days so that the things are deleted and ideally in the RAG as well, use metadata so that when the person is asking for a particular news, right?
Mayank: If, let's say, this is our AI revolution, ideally it will be in world, technology, or somewhere, okay?
Jayanth: Yep.
Jayanth: Actually.
Jayanth: This doesn't have the entire article stored in RAG. It only has metadata stored in RAG, actually. That's.
Mayank: That kind of works as well. Yeah, that still works.
Mayank: That works. Yeah, should be fine. I will go through the code. Very helpful.
Jayanth: Most of it is vibe coded, but I do know what's happening inside my phone.
Jayanth: I didn't let… complete the… I didn't let the AI take over.
Mayank: Can I share it with others? Other people are asking that. Yes, sure. Okay, don't be generous with the, sorry, don't be very generous with the AI usage. It will cost Jayant money. So you know this now, so just try it out, but otherwise.
Jayanth: I had a limitation of only about, $6 or $7 in the OpenAI, that one.
Jayanth: API link, so even if they use it too much, it's not gonna…
Mayank: Maybe it's still.
Mayank: The universe is still, like, 5, even 6, 7 dollars just for fun.
Jayanth: Yep.
Mayank: So it's still, but overall it's a pretty good application. Like, I am more interested. I will see the code about how you have done this thing because this all things are pretty good and straightforward. Like this is now pretty easy, which we can do, but yeah, how AI is handling it. Let me just ask a question only. Let's see.
Mayank: Hmm. You can, it's really good with the sources. Basically the data allowed.
Jayanth: There is some latency to it, but it does one, two or three seconds latency to it, but it does work.
Mayank: But overall, it's a good application. It is a good intermediate project. And plus you have, since you have hosted it as well, now I think it makes it very close to the kind of project which we are expected to do. Okay.
Jayanth: Yes.
Mayank: Good greet. Good greet, Jent.
Jayanth: Thank you. I will go through it.
Mayank: And, really thanks. I will try to see and see if we can use it somewhere after, of course, your permission. But yes, if you can teach it to everyone else, how you can do it, or if you are interested any day, you can teach that, hey, how you have done it, that would.
Jayanth: I didn't have that much knowledge. I know how things work, but I don't know in depth.
Mayank: I will do one thing. I will, once we do Landgraf, then one class, we will keep it for this where just 20 minutes you tell, and then I will take over and I will understand and do that and help you. Okay.
Jayanth: Okay.
Mayank: Remind me once so that I don't forget this.
Jayanth: Yes.
Mayank: Thank you Jayanta. Cool. Okay, so I think this patch is done. I think everyone is done, right? People who have talked to, please have the hands down.
Mayank: Okay, so okay people please.
Raju Kushwaha: Hello?
Mayank: Owned. Yes, Nigel.
Raju Kushwaha: Bye bye. Hello?
Mayank: Yes, yes, Raju.
Raju Kushwaha: I'm just, ping over chat. I can't, I don't want to, speak in front of everyone.
Mayank: No worries, you can send.
Raju Kushwaha: When it's a.
Mayank: Sorry, sorry, I was reading your message, actually. I got in between one minute.
Mayank: Raju, can you please send me your CV? What I will do is I will ask and forward it a little bit on priority so that you can get the package. Are you asking for that package if you will get it or is it something which you are normally getting?
Raju Kushwaha: No, no, actually, I am working behind the industry, but, I wanted to move into that field, so is it… not right… it's not urgent, but…
Mayank: Is it expected on what you're getting right now?
Raju Kushwaha: It's, getting at about less than 10, whatever I mentioned.
Raju Kushwaha: My, my thinking that, can I get that or not?
Mayank: You can, but again, I would love to understand a little bit in depth, like what exactly you have worked, because 20 years of experience in the relevant one can get you, of course, a lot more as well. So it depends on these things, ideally.
Raju Kushwaha: Mmhm.
Mayank: So just send me your CV. I will ask. I will get it right for you. But it's just 20 years of experience. The problem happens is the author package and many companies which I connect with, they are startups or something like not the bigger companies as of now. They are not very eager to hire the people with this level of experience because they don't have usage and they're in the trial mode.
Mayank: So… but still, let me try, if I can get something, I will surely…
Raju Kushwaha: Okay.
Mayank: So be sure to check it out.
Raju Kushwaha: Okay, man, thanks. Apart from this, I have one more question. Suppose I have, it's not… it might be not related to this. Suppose I have a Majin Bedrock, and I have purchased a Majin Bedrock, and it's inside of my premises.
Mayank: I don't.
Raju Kushwaha: And, and support, we are getting request from that model and support, there are two way. Either we can train the model so we can, get data per that, whatever, data.
Mayank: Fine tuning, you were saying?
Raju Kushwaha: And other… is there any other way to use the RAG also?
Mayank: Again, see, when you use Bedrock, Bedrock provides you with multiple things.
Debanjan Mani_Laptop: Models.
Mayank: monitoring and fine-tuning everything. So, it also provides you the knowledge bases. Knowledge bases are nothing but RAG there only, so you can use RAG inside that.
Raju Kushwaha: So if suppose we are, it's not inside our server, so they will train, but, if, we are going through that, so, for that we have to pay X amount. But if we're going to train that model, I have purchased only one time, and in the future we will, train that model, support any policy going to update, right? So need to train that model using that, latest policy and latest requirement rule. So is it good way or,
Raju Kushwaha: Do we need to do something, use the rack, like.
Mayank: No, I'.
Mayank: I'll get the requirement. See, you're using Amazon Bedrock. Amazon Bedrock provides you with a model. Now you're having some policies. Okay.
Raju Kushwaha: Right.
Mayank: Now, on top of that policies, what exactly is it that you want to do?
Raju Kushwaha: Suppose some rule has been changed. Suppose government had done some updated policy. So we need to update that model, right?
Mayank: But you will not be updating the model, model 2 will be there? You are… are.
Raju Kushwaha: One could, train data, we can, train the model again.
Mayank: And that is fine tuning when you train the model and everything. So are you fine tuning?
Raju Kushwaha: My question is, fine-tuning best option? Someone told that we can use the rack, they know…
Mayank: Drag is a.
Raju Kushwaha: Okay.
Mayank: not fine-tuning. RAG is a better option.
Raju Kushwaha: That is a better option. Okay.
Mayank: Yes, much better. See, fine-tuning is expensive. It takes a lot of time.
Raju Kushwaha: Okay.
Mayank: It is not going to still give you that. Plus, with the policies and everything, unless you are creating for a company-wide thing ki haabhi example, like Google is creating, Google wants to have a model.
Mayank: much optimized for Google, that is where Google can look at fine tuning and again, the smaller companies as well. But if you know that, hey, I have these policies only and this can get updated, all this can be handled by SQL RAG much better. Don't go for fine tuning. Okay.
Raju Kushwaha: Okay, so Rajiv will cover later, right?
Mayank: Yes, RAG we will be covering in a same manner. I have to still see how much depth I will be teaching. But yes, we will be covering RAG. Don't worry. Even if I take a month for RAG, I think it should be fine. I don't have any problem with that. So.
Raju Kushwaha: Okay, okay, thanks, man. I will share my review, man. Okay, and
Mayank: Just.
Raju Kushwaha: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Raju Kushwaha: I am going into correct direction or not. Main thingy package.
Mayank: Mainly you want to, you want to optimize package mainly, right?
Raju Kushwaha: Right, because I am here, I am here, fine, very news. I am managing a lot of things, but.
Mayank: I think you can get more than like what you're expecting you can get in Delhi. Again, it will depend on your previous experience. Experience wise, you can get for sure, but our experience for the 20 years of experience is fine for that package. But what you have done already, the work experience that will also have a say to it. So, send me your CV and I can help you with that.
Raju Kushwaha: Okay, sir. In the start, I, started my career from Rotten Development, then movement to RPA. I, did the master certification RTMSA anywhere also, Rupesh.
Mayank: That is fine, what I will do is I will forward your CV to Puma as well.
Mayank: that they have a requirement. So packaged though, I think they will be able to handle if you are good with things.
Raju Kushwaha: Okay, thanks. I'll, I'll, thank my, my, I will.
Mayank: Cool. Devanjan, I think… okay, Devanjan, I think you can share your screen. Actually, sorry.
Debanjan Mani_Laptop: Yeah, sure.
Mayank: Actually, new thing. Sorry.
Debanjan Mani_Laptop: Yeah, yeah,
Mayank: Let me do one thing.
Mayank: Although base creator evaluate module in Langsmith OpenAPI.
Mayank: LangChain Core. Why are you using LangChain Core? Where are you using it?
Debanjan Mani_Laptop: I'm, I'm just, I mean, I just, okay, here, let me show you.
Mayank: No, no, you can share the screen. People who I've talked to, please have your hands down.
Mayank: Next. Swathi, you are next.
suhasini: Yeah. Ma'am, can I speak now, or…
Mayank: Basically, you can speak, you can.
suhasini: I have, two, two couple of questions, ma'am. One is, first one is I, I wanted to build a, document editor kind of, an agent. Okay. Right. So where, it has a kind of a template where based on the user, selection over the template and he just, that template and wherever it requires, it has to implement that, whatever the, speech that, customer is giving. So that has to be converted to the text and, it has.
suhasini: to complete the document and generate a PDF that's one application which I want to implement so for this particular one I mean is it good to go with a code type of structure or is it okay to have go with already pre-built tools are available like right like already meet IO or I mean so there are some
suhasini: some couple of websites who are offering some kind of document editing and these types of tools, readily made tools, right? Which one will be the best?
Mayank: It will be available. It depends on your use case. Like, you want to edit the documents by voice. That's the requirement, right?
suhasini: Yeah, yeah, basically, by voice. Yes.
Mayank: So this, you can create your own as well. That should not be a problem, right? It's very easy now, thanks to AI. You can use any other as well, just that it depends now. If you're using your own C, ideally, voice to text is simple, like, voice is nothing difficult. It is just voice to text. Okay?
suhasini: And if I want to reduce the cost of this application, which freely available… I mean, are there any freely available models? I mean, the usage of the tool is also not so much, like maybe daily one or two document updates of maybe 50 pages each. So if that is the requirement…
Mayank: I think the free models should be able to handle it then. Like there are Nvidia models, et cetera and open router which do have 1 million context window.
Mayank: So, yes, they should be able to handle if there are one or two documents.
suhasini: Okay, okay, okay.
Mayank: That too should be doable.
suhasini: Okay. Okay then, Mayank, that is my first question, and the second question is, I have, like, 18 plus years of experience with seven, eight years of completely data science project works that I have done, and.
suhasini: very… I mean, having, 3 to 4, patents, 3 patents and 2 publications on my name.
suhasini: So, now I want to, move my career to the next level, so, which would be the right, choice of, things that I, I will, I can focus on. Like, as of now, I, I am a completely, I am into a data science, project manage, I mean, project lead, I can say. But, now I'm thinking which one will be a better, career move.
suhasini: Maybe your suggestion?
Mayank: You can move to, if you, I think if you are having patents and research, that's pretty impressive. You can move to some research kind of a thing as well, like where you are having the research kind of a companies, Google DeepMind and all these things. Every, like every of these bigger companies, they are having their department. I think that is honestly the best one for you. Like if you enjoy that level of in depth plus,
Mayank: If you are, on the other hand, want to optimize for money and that, then I think you can move towards the AI architect or that kind of role at 18 years of experience.
suhasini: That should be more.
Mayank: more than enough. You can create that kind of a role because it will be paying good, it will be doing justice. Because if you're having a data science experience, people in data science are only leading AI teams.
suhasini: Yes.
Mayank: So that's one of very simple approach that people who are in data science, they are the only one who are now leading AI teams. So that experience is very, very helpful. If you have patent and everything, just go towards any of these kind of things where if you're interested in research site.
suhasini: Yeah, but my patents are related to a particular segment, you can say, like.
Mayank: Should not be a problem. That is never seen.
Mayank: Yeah, because the patent is a big thing first, but second is that, of course, if it is a very particular part of that as well, right, then also it should find, provided you can explain that, hey, I think good to understand in depth and everything. So that should not be a problem. Rather, that's a positive that you have patents. I would say that optimize for a research-based role where you, if you enjoy those things.
suhasini: Yeah, to go to a architect role kind of, currently myself, I'm, I'm into like, a complete, data science, kind of like majority of my, work is into exploring lot of things and how we can solve a particular problem, that kind of, I mean, feature definitions, how things will go in into the model and how we train the model. So majority of my experience is into that. But, going for an AI architect.
suhasini: correct role, right? They ask for entire end-to-end, like, you know, DevOps, MLOps.
Mayank: So you should be having that with the experience, right? If you're having a series of experience, you should have done that. Hence, when we will do projects, just add that to your CV. I'm pretty sure that you will having that. Anyways, you will have that knowledge. It just need a little bit of polishing. But I would suggest that don't.
suhasini: Here we go.
Mayank: So just give interviews. After three, four interviews, it will start making sense. No one knows all the things in interview. I don't know. So no one.
suhasini: Okay.
Mayank: In this world, we know that, hey, I know everything for this role. So yeah, just don't focus on that. You have a stellar CV, stellar patents, research experience, use that. I would highly suggest to just join some biggest companies with their research departments. That's going to pay good and everything. Or otherwise, smaller companies at a very higher level, like let's say below CTO at 18 years of experience, that would also work. Or as a CXO or CTO as well. If you are having that good experience, then it should be helpful.
suhasini: Yeah, yeah, yeah. Thanks for your suggestion, man. Thank you, thank you so much.
Mayank: Deepanjan, I'm waiting for you to share your screen. I've given you the panelist access, no?
Debanjan Mani_Laptop: Yeah, yeah, I'm just waiting.
Mayank: Share the screen. No, you can share. I'm taking questions so that you can share it parallelly. You should have shared. I would have stopped there. I pinged you as well. Extremely sorry that you have to wait.
Debanjan Mani_Laptop: No, no, that'.
Mayank: that I'm trying to handle all the questions, yeah.
Debanjan Mani_Laptop: Yeah. So this is the, yeah.
Mayank: Is it a complete laptop kya?
Debanjan Mani_Laptop: No, no, no, it'.
Mayank: Land chain agents import create digits.
Debanjan Mani_Laptop: Yeah, it's a usual, like, get weather function,
Mayank: Oh.
Debanjan Mani_Laptop: date when it was posted.
Debanjan Mani_Laptop: So I'm getting this,
Mayank: Just scroll down a little bit. I'm not able to see the error.
Debanjan Mani_Laptop: Just a minute.
Mayank: Port data.
Debanjan Mani_Laptop: This is scroll.
Mayank: So WebEx, can I scroll down? Module LangChain code available based on module LangSmith. Have you made sure that if there was any earlier version of LangChain that has been removed properly, or are you creating at least a new environment?
Debanjan Mani_Laptop: No, I have not done new environment.
Mayank: Mehraba, I think that is where it is failing. So it is trying to load it from LangChain core enables. Let me try to see it.
Debanjan Mani_Laptop: Okay.
Debanjan Mani_Laptop: Okay, alright, fine.
Mayank: No, it will not be if you create a new environment. I think there is a version problem. Let's quickly check. Let me quickly check it.
Mayank: Okay… Can you do one thing? Hello? Just…
Debanjan Mani_Laptop: Yeah, yeah.
Mayank: Install LangChain, LangChain Core, and LangSmith, all three together. Because I feel right now, what is the problem is that you have installed LangChain, okay? But LangSmith is a previous version. You must have installed LangSmith somewhere earlier. So they are not matching. So there's a compatibility thing, right?
Debanjan Mani_Laptop: Okay.
Mayank: So just run this command which I'm sending you.
Mayank: One minute. I sent you the command. Just I think you will not be able to copy it. What are you able to do?
Debanjan Mani_Laptop: Okay. If fine, I'm stopping to sharing my screen, but, import. Okay. All right. All right. Let me check. Fine. Let me, stop sharing.
Mayank: Madhav, if you want, we can fix it together. I'm sharing you the code share link. I've sent everyone. Madhav, I've shared the code share link. I've copied the code. But, the problem is this only. Majorly, it's a version mismatch, nothing else.
Debanjan Mani_Laptop: Let me stop sharing my screen,
Mayank: Oh.
Debanjan Mani_Laptop: Let me run this on.
Mayank: Just try to run this, paste the output beneath and I will give you the answer email. Okay, so you can stop the sharing if you want. Not a problem, but it is that only. I don't think it will be anything else. Either you can create a new environment from scratch, but I think right now it is using the current environment or something. I'm not sure what this language in course is, so it should be fine.
Debanjan Mani_Laptop: We'll find out. Let me try to find this issue.
Mayank: Great. People who have talked to please have hands down. Harshit?
Harshit Goyal: Yeah, hi, Mike. Mike, just, I dropped you a mail regarding the projects. If you can share…
Mayank: I'm able to go through my email one minute.
Mayank: Actually, there were lots of emails around 14 minutes, so I thought ki should I will do it after the classes.
Harshit Goyal: Yeah, yeah, sure, sure. Not in hurry, but then if you can share, that would be a good help, because there are some of the interviews probably will line up for me in, let's say, next month. So, I want to just add those going through with the projects and stuff, yeah.
Mayank: okay let me see actually the problem is that which I'm having it is I think a hidden directory so that's the very first problem private directory agentic AIE the one where I'm having this that's a private one there I'm having at least four projects just two time to make sure one thing you don't if there is any key don't use it.
Harshit Goyal: Don't worry.
Mayank: In their directory, there are projects, some projects. Otherwise, these are good to start with. These are pretty good.
Mayank: So I'm just sending you the directory by expanding it. I will be doing it in classes as well, although I have to make them a little bit better because it has been around four or five months since I worked on them. I did blocking for security reason.
Harshit Goyal: It's, you're replying me on mail, right.
Mayank: I'm trying to. It's… I'm giving… I was sending you a zip.
Harshit Goyal: Okay.
Mayank: I think it is not letting me say it because of something. It's a code, right? So it might be able to flag it up. One minute.
Mayank: Meanwhile, next one is Ramakrishna.
Ramakrishna P: Hi, Mayank. Yeah, I have actually long, close long years of experience. I'm trying to understand your requirement, right? My job opportunity you have given, right? So is that okay? I, shall I change my profile or is it, only for five plus or five years like that? But amazing.
Mayank: It's your user experience.
Ramakrishna P: 11 years, closely, but most of the 7 to 8 years into Java distributed systems as full stack.
Ramakrishna P: Yeah, 3 to 4 years into this park, and I can't do this.
Mayank: If you are fine with the job description and the…
Mayank: money, because I think the maximum will be around 30-35 for both the roles.
Ramakrishna P: Okay, okay.
Mayank: If you are fine with that, you can apply. If at your experience you feel that, hey, money is not good and I can then know because, like again, considering the job market as of now, I think any job is good, but if you are having it, because see, I don't want that you miss out on that, but then at the end of the day, it's not a complete, complete company, right?
Ramakrishna P: Mmhm.
Mayank: But just see, I think for your use case, then the, that is a better call ki if the money justifies and roll in money. So.
Mayank: Let's try that.
Ramakrishna P: Okay, I will send you…
Mayank: But first, see, because again, I have to sit through every CV. So I will be kind of promoting first, which are 3, 2, 5, 4, 6 years of experience requirement. Okay, if you will be overqualified, then also it's a problem. Company sees it as HR, we have to, we need a 3 to 6 years experience person. It is having 11 years. So he might not leave after some time. So those are decisions. Just try to make it up.
Ramakrishna P: Okay.
Mayank: whether that would be a little helpful. Just, if you send it, it should not be a problem. I will surely try. But I will have to see. If I get example 50 CVs, I cannot forward all 50s. That would be a problem.
Mayank: Okay, so if you feel that yes, I'm fine with everything, that should not be a problem. So I think .
Ramakrishna P: Okay.
Mayank: Okay.
Debanjan Mani_Laptop: Yeah, Mayank, I just visited the versions that are showing.
Mayank: I have pinged you the next command. Just force reinstall them. Ideally, the best case dimension would be if you can create an environment. Okay, delete the previous installation because I feel that is a problem. Like the code was very simple, which you were trying to run. It is running on Polab, right?
Debanjan Mani_Laptop: Yeah, yeah, it is running on Po.
Mayank: Just reinstall them, force reinstall them. Otherwise, what I would suggest is just have a completely new environment. Okay. And it should be able to work it out. Your version is 0.1.
Mayank: And it should be able to work it out. Your version is point, well, version is also not very older. Like I think there is some file problem only. Like maybe when you installed, it might have rewritten some file that some might have been there, but that kind of issue it seems because these are very simple more like the, there is no required that as well.
Debanjan Mani_Laptop: No.
Mayank: Parallelly also share your, also paste your code on that same link, which I've given you. After my 15th line, just share your code.
Basavanna Olekar: Yeah, can you hear me?
Mayank: Yes, sir.
Basavanna Olekar: This is wrong. Yeah. First thing, like, you know, Jayant has, like, you know, you pinged the Jayant link, right? For one of the project he did on the new search. I just clicked on it. It, I'm not able to open, is that right?
Mayank: Eas.
Basavanna Olekar: Show me the…
Mayank: I don't think it is an access issue. I don't think Jayant is there. It is opening, maybe. Are you on an office laptop by any chance?
Basavanna Olekar: No, no, no, I'm on my personal.
Mayank: So, Jayith will have to tell that. Pallav, I don't think it.
Basavanna Olekar: I'm in the US. Does that make a difference? No, right?
Mayank: Should not. Again, Jayanta has done that. So Jayanta is online. People are able to open. Just check. It is an HTTPS server. Everything is fine there. Should not be a problem. I'm not sure. Like maybe there is some firewall thing or something because I'm also able to open it up and it's not that heavy at least. Venky is from US and she's also able to access it. So.
Basavanna Olekar: Okay.
Mayank: Oh.
Basavanna Olekar: Second question was like curiosity, like when you are interviewing, especially for Agentic AI positions, would you focus on Python, Python coding, best practices, SQL, data modeling also, or else?
Mayank: I do. I personally focus more on software side and the understanding that how does a particular person solve the problem and then AI gets integrated. Because for me, AI or agents, these are just some components. So if a person is having a better understanding of software development cycle, that's a much better thing because that person can easily integrate AI into anything, right?
Mayank: The reason is, if it's the other way around that a person just knows LangChain and LangGraph, of course, even in depth, but he's having a little bit loose end in the development side, then that's a problem. Although, as I said, like in this, by the end of this batch, you will have that understanding why I projects and everything. But I tried, I will not ask them Python basics, but at least I will expect that they can explain what is happening why, because I also understand no one is.
Mayank: Going to write the code from scan, but yeah, at least whatever code is given, that should be,
Basavanna Olekar: Pretty much production gear.
Mayank: Any person to be able to explain that?
Mayank: And you should know at least that if there is a Pydantic library, you should know these things up at least.
Basavanna Olekar: Okay, okay.
Mayank: Okay, but Mike, if you… Oh, sorry, yeah, sorry.
Basavanna Olekar: No, no, no, please go.
Mayank: No, no, I was saying that my focus is to see the problem solving ability plus whatever previous work the person has done. That is what I focused a little bit on.
Basavanna Olekar: Okay. Is there any way, like, you know, we can have a centralized place where we can see how many, people are there in my batch, how to connect with them? Because like, you know, whenever you attend a course, it's not only the knowledge, but the network also helps.
Mayank: So, there is that group which is there, like nothing else can be there. So, the group is there which we can use.
Basavanna Olekar: Okay. Okay. And the only request is for all the audience, if interview questions and the challenges and the outcome can be shared, other people can, it can help other people to prepare accordingly.
Mayank: Yes. There, I would suggest that if you are giving an interview, anyone, if you are passing it up or anything, just forward it to me, and I will add it either through the link or through the GitHub.
Basavanna Olekar: Yeah, like, how much it was challenging, and like, you know.
Mayank: That I will add to the GitHub, I will add to.
Basavanna Olekar: That would be helpful. It's just a request actually. Yeah.
Mayank: I mean, if.
Basavanna Olekar: It's.
Mayank: We'll give that, that should be helpful, yeah.
Basavanna Olekar: Thanks, thanks a lot.
Mayank: Yep.
Mayank: OK. Next is Anju.
Anshul: Hey, man. Hi.
Mayank: Yes.
Anshul: Mayank, I have a couple of questions, okay? So,
Debanjan Mani_Laptop: Yeah, I'm sure, sorry, sorry to interrupt, just one thing. Mayak, do you want me to share the, like, gate weather code again?
Mayank: Is that code which you are facing under the block of code?
Debanjan Mani_Laptop: Yeah, yeah, yeah. Okay.
Mayank: Just paste it and paste it. Essentials. Sorry.
Anshul: No problem.
Anshul: So first one is just a clarification. So what I understood today that in the state and runtime, we can pass in custom data, custom fields, right?
Mayank: We can pass custom fields as well, yeah.
Anshul: So, is there any difference if I pass a custom field in, let's say, state, or for that matter, in runtime context? Or is it the same?
Mayank: if you pass it in the state versus the runtime context if you want to pass anything okay yes I think I have to answer that I forgot that okay so see if you are passing something okay.
Mayank: which is going, let me clear that tomorrow, but yeah, let me see that. If it is mutable, okay, if let's say there is something which you want to mutate as the time, for example, user ID will not be mutable. The number of calls will be mutable that you will go by state. Okay. If you want it to persist across sessions, sorry, across different, let's say invokes. Okay.
Anshul: Mmh.
Mayank: Then you should pass it on state, Context forgets it. So that is the best decision, I think, which you can take. So mutability and persistence. If you want it to be persist across multiple invocations and mutability, then state, otherwise context. I forget to answer this question, I did research on the same during the break, but yeah.
Anshul: Because somewhere in LangChain docs, I read that state is mutable, and
Anshul: Runtime context is unmutable, so I was really confused.
Mayank: No, no, no, you're right, you're right. I kind of, so this question was asked, I actually just got it confused with some other framework. So that's why I said that, let me answer it. I did the research during the break and you are right, state is mutable. I will create it tomorrow in the class, the first thing.
Anshul: No problem, no problem.
Mayank: Okay, so that decision help us that, hey, if you want it to persist and if you want it to be immutable, then it's more than enough.
Anshul: Okay, okay. Second question, Mayank, is, so now, so we have, we have runtime and state, right? So there is one option, if I define a tool, let's say if I define Adaraid tool, then I can access runtime and state in the tool call, and I can use the data to set up the context, additional context, right?
Mayank: Reward.
Anshul: yeah yeah but versus when I let's say when I wrap a tool using a middleware let's say wrap more wrap tool call right and in that I I fetch the tool runtime and then I use the data to further you know let's optimize my context so the question is that so when I use a wrap to for a tool that particular context which I let's say change in the tool call.
Anshul: It stays… it stays for that particular, model, or for that particular model call, versus.
Anshul: If I, let's say, access runtime and state in a normal tool call, not in a middleware, then it stays throughout my, let's say, that particular agent invocation. Is that true? Because I have some confusion here that when to use what?
Mayank: With respect to the runtime and state.
Anshul: Yes, yes, yes.
Mayank: If you want to have any value which you want to maintain across multiple runs, example booking, let's say in this particular run or any loaded skill or anything which you want to change, okay, number of calls, that is what will coincide. That will persist across multiple invocation.
Mayank: But anything which you want to set in the starting, which your agent might use, example, user ID, any DB connection credentials, those are the one which you would save in the context in the runtime. Just that.
Anshul: No, my question is with respect to the tool call. Tool call.
Mayank: Yes, coming to the phone call, yeah.
Anshul: Yeah, so I can call, or I can use runtime and state at two different points in the invocation. One is, I define a tool, let's say, at the rate tool. It's not a middleware, it's just a tool.
Anshul: And in the tool… when I call that tool, then I'm using the runtime and state to play around with the existing data and the context, whatever I want to do.
Mayank: This is Runtime Institute.
Anshul: Yeah, versus I am trying to, now, wrap a tool, using wrap tool call.
Anshul: So in that tool call, also, along with all the information, I also get the runtime and state.
Mayank: Yes, s.
Anshul: In the raptor code.
Mayank: Yes.
Anshul: And then I can use that information. So, question is, so… so, when I do a wrap tool call.
Anshul: Then, when that particular tool is called, before that, the wrap tool call will be called, right? And based on what I'm doing inside it, it will further, change my, let's say, let's say arguments of the tool, probably.
Mayank: you want to change.
Mayank: Based, yeah.
Anshul: And then it's gonna hit the tool and give me the result. Now, next time… next time, when the same tool is called in same invocation, then, again, the… again, the same model… same, wrap tool call will be used to, change the.
Mayank: Running reporter model tool, yeah.
Anshul: Yes, yes, yes. Now, so this is middleware.
Anshul: Now, let's say, for a particular tool, I'm not wrapping it with the wrap tool call, but I'm still calling that tool… but my agent is still… or the model is still suggesting to call that particular tool. In that tool, I have defined runtime and state, and I'm using the data.
Anshul: Run demonstrate data to play around with the context, okay?
Anshul: So the question is, when that cool tool is called, while the invocation is happening, not the wrap one, then whatever changes I do before the tool is actually called, will that change stay in my next tool? Let's say the same tool is called in, let's say, the third model call. Understood.
Anshul: Yeah, so…
Mayank: That is, again, let's see.
Mayank: If it is all in the same invocation.
Anshul: Okay.
Mayank: Runtime will have a context which you cannot change because it is not mutable. So, it will have the same values. If you are changing the state, you can change the state and it will persist. So, let's say number of calls, you can make it one, two or three. Every tool call, along with state and runtime, it will get some other values as well. So, that other value is totally on you if you want to change or what you want to do.
Mayank: So if you want to change the argument because every tool call will have a separate argument. So only the state are the changes which will be there. So that would be the case. Like only the state are the one which will persist and you can mutate them. Arguments, name of tool, everything will be anyways for every call, it will be the new value based on what model suggests. Runtime, as long as it is working in a single invoke, it will be having the values which you can use if you require.
Mayank: Good.
Anshul: Okay, okay. Okay, got it. Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. And the last question is, so when we, let's say, so is this part of the syntax when I write at the rate wrap model call or wrap tool call? Is it the syntax in itself or I can use any name for as per my convenience whenever I want to either wrap a tool or wrap a model?
Mayank: So in the wrap, when you have that thing, if you're defining it as a decorator, you can just use that in any name.
Anshul: If…
Mayank: If you are defining it with respect to the class, if you remember, right? We can create decorators via class as well. So there is a decorator via class v. When you're defining it with class, I think that you have to use the same name.
Anshul: Okay. Okay.
Mayank: So just to explain you, I hope you're able to get it. But what I mentioned was, let me share the screen. Let's see. So when you are getting with a decorator based, you can have any name and you can just wrap it like this before model, log before model, and it will happen before model. But when you're defining it with respect to a class based, then I remember the name should be same. Then this name is actually what it catches.
Mayank: So agent middleware, you are actually overwriting this before model. So if the name will be different, the exact function will not be overrated. So it will not be called. So see, after model, before model, all this is happening here.
Anshul: Okay, so this is the class-based middleware, right?
Mayank: This is same middleware, just based, just created using class. Earlier one was using decorator. The benefits I discussed, you can have multiple directly here, both async, multiple hooks needed in a single middleware, complex configuration. So that is the case, but yes, here the need would be the same.
Anshul: Okay, okay. And just, an additional question. So, this last question, guys, please, excuse me for that.
Anshul: So, let's say when we have multiple middlewares in the create agent, you know.
Anshul: I have a before model, I have an after model, I have a wrapped model or a wrapped tool call.
Anshul: So, does sequencing of these, middlewares, does it, does it matter? It matters.
Mayank: Okay.
Anshul: Developer.
Mayank: middleware one, two and three. So first middleware one before agent would be called. So we have a middleware and inside a middleware we can have that where you want to actually hook it.
Mayank: Okay? So that is where before agent one is called. Then before model, then wrap model call. Okay?
Mayank: Then of course when the tool will be called based on that particular middleware, if it is on top of tool, then that will be used. Okay. Then after model, then after agent. So here you will see it reversing.
Anshul: Yeah, so for example, if I have defined two middlewares, one is… first, I've defined wrap model call, and then I defined before model. So, if the sequence is this, then always wrap model will be called first, and then there is no use of…
Mayank: No, no, no, before model will be called first.
Anshul: Yeah, so that's what I was asking. So, in wrap model and before model, or let's say after model, it can be in any sequence. Lenkin is intelligent enough to identify which to call first.
Mayank: There are two things. First is if there is a single one, let's say just only middleware one is there.
Anshul: Mmh.
Mayank: Okay, then it calls it like this. Right.
Mayank: then it calls it something like this before model then tool and models are based on when you'll be calling it then after model after agent okay.
Mayank: Now, in a single middleware as well, you can have multiple places where you want LVMs are seen. Now, when we have multiple ones, then that is where this thing comes into picture.
Mayank: This will be in a reverse manner, if you will see. This is afterwards. The agent which executed the very first before agent, it should close in the end. Because it can have dependencies which were based on that. Middleware 2 might have something based on Middleware 1. So which opened first, the gate which opened first, it can have, it has to close last idly. Clear? Okay. Understood. So that is the thing. Yeah.
Mayank: Last piece of thing from my side, I think you shared that coupon to get a free course on Udemy, right? It is about having some limit, though. Yeah, no problem. I was one of the lucky ones. I've got it.
Anshul: Okay, understood, understood.
Mayank: That is the thing.
Anshul: Yeah. Yeah, just last piece of, thing from my side. I think you shared that, coupon to get a free course on Udemy, right?
Mayank: It is about having some limit, so it might be…
Anshul: Yeah, no problem.
Mayank: Good news.
Anshul: I was one of the lucky ones, I've.
Mayank: Okay.
Anshul: And then probably someone in between tried to, you know, say something, and I understand you are experienced enough to avoid such sort of things. Someone was saying that, please get along with concept.
Mayank: Oh, I should.
Anshul: There'.
Mayank: Not a problem.
Anshul: It's just my advice to people in this room, guys. You may be some really good person, really intelligent person, and if you are so, then you should not be part of such a session. I think you are here to learn something, and if something is being offered with such generosity, please accept it with some, you know, some modesty and all. I mean, don't try to…
Mayank: It's totally fine, like…
Anshul: Yeah, yeah, yeah. I understand.
Mayank: All of you benefit, so it doesn't matter.
Anshul: Trainer, I understand you cannot say a lot, because.
Mayank: Thank you.
Anshul: your experience enough, but at least I can say I can take that liberty. Yeah.
Mayank: Thanks a lot, but I think it doesn't matter as such. It should be fine. Like every person has other views. Just my humble request is anyone who is getting it, please use it because these are generally very much in depth courses and yeah, two rate assessments so that it reaches out to other people as well. And as, as it gets refreshed, I will keep on sharing the coupons of future courses and otherwise.
Mayank: That is, I think.
Anshul: Great, thank you, thank you.
Mayank: Thank you. Thanks, Rajeshwar. Sorry. Okay, I think there was one more person left, Hardik.
Hardik Vora: Hey, Mayank. Hi. Thanks. Mayank, sorry I asked you to a bit, slow, but I was writing the note.
Mayank: No no no.
Hardik Vora: I was writing your note.
Mayank: Okay.
Hardik Vora: Usually, you mentioned some…
Mayank: Totally fine.
Hardik Vora: No worries.
Mayank: I have to be sorry to be.
Hardik Vora: No problem. No, so mine couple of things. This tool underscore RT which you mentioned I mean you had earlier you had mentioned tool RT and then I asked you is it a different So what exactly is the difference in tool RT with respect to add tools?
Mayank: I will teach that in the language graph part only.
Hardik Vora: Okay, it's under Langra.
Mayank: I think I remember it. I think it was in the previous one or something. I even have to revise it. I was writing the code.
Hardik Vora: Mmh.
Mayank: was something, I forget exactly what it was, but I will revise it and just tell them. Keep that, keep it too long, they should be fine.
Hardik Vora: Sure. Another thing is in today's discussion. So Mayank, you mentioned earlier as well that you mentioned high in cloud, right? So it usually takes a context. I mean, I'm just ensuring that all the dots are.
Mayank: Internal resources.
Hardik Vora: Here, okay, what you are explaining. So today you have mentioned on, custom interruption and all. I mean, that is fine. But, if those conversations are long, what you are, storing in the state and runtime, which we were discussing in detail, right? You explained it very clearly. It appreciated that I understood the last session where I was asking you question.
Mayank: Fine.
Hardik Vora: argument issues, so today…
Mayank: VAR.
Hardik Vora: Yeah, I told you that.
Mayank: That's why I tried KEHAM before. Actually, that was the main thing. So, well, before going to jump, jumping to MCP, I thought that, okay, let me now make, so thanks you for that, KEMC.
Hardik Vora: It was very clear today. Yeah.
Mayank: Put that on there just in.
Hardik Vora: State and runtime and tool request. I clearly understood now why it was happening earlier and thanks for explaining in detail. So on that conversation, you mentioned that state has all the messages, right? We, it's towards in the conversation and it goes to agent. So I asked you in the question in the chat earlier, but I think in the session you missed it. So just trying to reiterate, just in case the chat or the conversations are very long.
Hardik Vora: Right? So it, uses of much of the tokens and the context. And then, we see in your cloud that you write high, it first takes for 4.5 k and then maximum it, it goes to your, 37 k, right? What we've seen. So just, the semantic, context as per the message, if I want to optimize in the existing code, how should we implement it? So semantic question is.
Mayank: Is it?
Hardik Vora: Okay, my question is, daily you come, you ask, today you ask some other topic, tomorrow you ask some other topic, after a month you ask the one month earlier topic, which is only related to that semantic context.
Hardik Vora: So what is happening now in your high message, in your Claude, what I've seen, it takes every time it takes, 30, 35, 37 k token, which is of.
Mayank: Yes.
Hardik Vora: Not… I mean, I'm just trying to understand, just correct me. It is not…
Mayank: One minute.
Hardik Vora: Yeah. Okay.
Mayank: Hello?
Hardik Vora: Yeah, are you… are you able to hear me?
Mayank: Okay, just a minute. Am I audible, everyone?
Hardik Vora: Yeah, yeah, you are.
Mayank: Anybody?
Hardik Vora: Hello. Are you able to hear me?
Debanjan Mani_Laptop: My ankles maybe dropped off, like, the knee joint.
Hardik Vora: Yeah, yeah, I just saw that. I think he is.
Mayank: Yeah, sorry, sorry, Hardik. Yeah, sorry. I think very weird internet issue. Yeah, yeah, no problem.
Hardik Vora: Good morning.
Hardik Vora: Yeah, yeah, you are aud.
Mayank: Great. Sorry. Yeah.
Hardik Vora: So, Mike, I hope you have the context. So what I'm trying to ask is, the optimization perspective on the chat message which we do. So can't we take it in the semantics of that messages from the state only? What?
Mayank: Sorry, sorry, can you repeat it? There was a drop.
Hardik Vora: Okay, no problem. So, what I was discussing that you mentioned high, and you… you, get 30… 35K tokens…
Mayank: Yeah, it sends lots of things around with that.
Hardik Vora: But what I'm… I'm trying to optimize from what today you have explained, state and runtime, right?
Mayank: Yep.
Hardik Vora: So, in state, you mentioned that we have all the conversation messages. Now, I am trying.
Mayank: In Langchain, yes, I believe we have that.
Hardik Vora: So, what I'm trying, to optimize is to reduce all the irrelevant, calls happening in the… all the conversation memory, which we did for, suppose, 6 months.
Mayank: Yes.
Hardik Vora: For 6 months.
Hardik Vora: So why to get all of those instead of it just taking on the semantics of the messages which has been stored earlier, that only it can optimize and it can give you from the tokens perspective or from the, so how can we build such kind of thing in this context?
Mayank: So we have memory, long term memory, right?
Hardik Vora: Hmm?
Mayank: Now, in memory, we have multiple, like, again, with respect to memory as well, we have implementations, like MemZero supports that natively, where you can ask it, and it will just get the relevant memories by semantics and by checking it out.
Hardik Vora: Mmh.
Mayank: So we will have to make sure that we are able to create it in this manner that, and again, it is totally on us, so we can either get all the memories, we can get paste on that, we can get all the information. So that will depend on the long term store, which is in runtime, right?
Hardik Vora: Hmm. Okay.
Mayank: So whenever we are sending a message, let's say a simple hi, we can define the values there. It can be based on logic. Of course, lots of middleware and functions will be written, but we will check based on, let's say, the number of messages which I've shown you. Those keys, we will load the relevant ones. Now, Claude, how it handles it versus we, it is totally on us.
Hardik Vora: So, Claude might have already optimized. I'm just thinking, so, Claude may be maximum optimization kay I know.
Mayank: Kiyogallikhin nahi yaasan muta. Kiyogdhari kiyogdharis ka.
Mayank: What is your experience with CHADENA?
Hardik Vora: Okay.
Mayank: MCP level PBRs. For now, Claude is burning monies anyway.
Hardik Vora: Mmm.
Mayank: People will be mad.
Hardik Vora: People will attract and correct.
Mayank: So, wo ek balance optimization akhte hai? Wahdi application ma'am hai woh kaali reni uthe ki ki k.
Mayank: We can take that up.
Hardik Vora: Hmm, hmm. So is the optimization in state k messaging terms, how can we optimize?
Mayank: Ideally, when we are starting a new chat app, right?
Hardik Vora: Mmm.
Mayank: We have seen that already as well.
Hardik Vora: Okay.
Mayank: Second is ki, memory jo hai, long term memory hai, short term dohar agini padaga. Long term memory hai, don't try to settle a.
Mayank: SUSMI, we are very cautious about… we are loading them as only on the… based on the number of messages.
Mayank: We will add to see kya kya pala context fil kya se ho raha hai? Jaja jaas kya kya kya kya kya kya kya kya ky.
Hardik Vora: Just two points up. Can you please, I mean, mention again, I'll, I'll, I'll just write it down. What two optimizations we should do?
Mayank: So I am saying first thing is that we will see ki what exactly is causing the context filling or the context cephalon.
Hardik Vora: m.
Mayank: Two years.
Hardik Vora: Okay.
Mayank: Second is that there is a major context where MCP tools fit in.
Mayank: In this message, it loads some tools up.
Hardik Vora: Correct.
Mayank: That is where it gets a little bit loaded. Toh woham dekhingi, se uske lava hum long-term memory mein dekhingi ki, exactly vahasik ka kajara long-term memory se. Okay. When you start a chat, toh short-term memory toh kuch ho thi nahi nahi.
Hardik Vora: Right.
Mayank: So, we try to just make sure ki eko long-term memory, which is Mahari, any store, like, in-memory store, kya SQL store, k.
Hardik Vora: Mmhm.
Mayank: And parallelly, memory and parallelly are the tools. I don't think his custom instructions, etc, are so long, so that should not be a problem there.
Hardik Vora: Okay, okay. So, we can try to optimize for our applications.
Mayank: Exactly. Pallab, we have to just see khemara contains burkis sarai. Whatever is filling up our context, let's try to nail down and enter it up.
Hardik Vora: And, Jason Mayank, we have seen in, I mean, open code and a visual code with open source agent, what we are getting run vs code kajo automatically agent hotai right auto alamodomi So they usually try to optimize automatically in our context filling, right?
Mayank: Oh, oh.
Hardik Vora: They try. So, just on top of what you've explained just now.
Hardik Vora: Context filling ka, if I want to keep track, okay, how much it is getting stored, your percentage, percentage of cloud path, right? 6%, 10%.
Mayank: No, sure.
Hardik Vora: Us ko hum kese going in the every every conversation us ko optimize karne ki context filling ko track karna.
Mayank: So, let's say, for example.
Hardik Vora: Mmm.
Mayank: Jabhamniya abhiyajeevanayatam niy.
Hardik Vora: Dynamic running, huh.
Mayank: So, usmeh bhiya khanna ki mihi.
Hardik Vora: Mmhm.
Mayank: User walajo usernejo ki kuch commands ki ai user ki custom instruction hoskar kita n.
Hardik Vora: Mmh.
Mayank: So, ideally, you want to have a plus plus kar k.
Hardik Vora: Right.
Mayank: Post me up notice kar langi ki kis ka kitna naar aay clod bhi aay kar thao hav jaise example ke liye.
Hardik Vora: Mmhm.
Mayank: Kitna hai hamar ko patajis ka k.
Hardik Vora: I mean, you.
Mayank: So those are the instructions that I am asking.
Hardik Vora: Okay.
Mayank: Tools yaar bloho nahi hai tham tool ka bhi nik.
Mayank: Jessica kar kyu jessica watermeli kh.
Hardik Vora: Okay.
Mayank: Me sushil meklor bhanw.
Mayank: Definitely.
Hardik Vora: Nahi, madhab abhijisthari ki se wo kloradka example ki jo relate karthi ana ki what we.
Hardik Vora: we should build, how we should optimize perspective, say not as such clone of cloud, but at least understanding ki how they are implementing in their architectural perspective ki ki system design to I'm not aware. So the way you are explaining in a topic level, I'm just trying to relate the dots ki kaise.
Mayank: Nee, aapkurti ki karna study. Humbanah sathere wo bhanjayaga sahin tadi karna karna karna karna karna karna karna karna karna karna karna.
Hardik Vora: Mmh.
Mayank: Kuch kuch kuch ki aur jadhav kuch kuch ki aur jadhav software lang akhyushku.
Hardik Vora: Correct. I have seen what you have taught. I mean, I am very relatable. Nobody's understanding in detail how quickly people are building applications from ChatGPT.
Hardik Vora: Why it is.
Mayank: Got it.
Hardik Vora: it is of you. Haan, that is what I'm trying to relate now ki mala over over skill or a overkill or ochi so mein but.
Mayank: No.
Hardik Vora: Now I understand what you are explaining for a wrap and wrap tool or custom, middleware method. I'm still a bit, confused because not implemented.
Mayank: They were implemented a long time ago.
Mayank: Bora.
Hardik Vora: Telling me about it.
Mayank: Before, before I went to RAP, karthik karthik karthik karthik exec.
Hardik Vora: -H.
Mayank: Tabus ki baas, wo bhi ajat hai. Before model mein toh ki aap model ko call kar n.
Hardik Vora: Bailey.
Hardik Vora: which is very good optimization. I understood.
Mayank: Exactly. Jabhab wrapped karthir na tool ya model ko. Toh samil le jabhus ko call karthir kuch kar on kar k.
Hardik Vora: Mmm.
Mayank: Before me, okay, ki bae, aapko kaal khanna aapko pata hai chalot hi kaar. Aap ramte aus ki.
Mayank: that it is helpful. Before the tool, there were a lot of arguments. There was a lot of talk about kaafki khiche sa padaaya kaara bhi bais k.
Hardik Vora: Yeah, in detail, more revision comes.
Mayank: They were revision prototyp.
Hardik Vora: kk khar raytheaj tak to. It is not normal like not to make it difficult. I'm just asking ki generically agar ko application build karte to consistency mein.
Mayank: So, SM, it is not normal, like, not to make it difficult, SM in a data class use kh.
Hardik Vora: Maybe I'm just asking.
Hardik Vora: ki generically agar koi application build karte to consistency mein payden tikwada use kar ki is optimized.
Mayank: So, it is fine. I don't have a data class. I don't have a data class. So, it is fine. The fit is not a problem.
Hardik Vora: And the classes, custom classes, where we usually use multiple things, right?
Hardik Vora: which serves a purpose for one, agentic call. I mean, user call kali, kushala class manalia to, I mean, just trying to understand my gap kay experience me agentic applications one tier or multiple classes hum jab banate to uska, mallab in memory me calling kay time pay execution kay time pay. Is there any delay what you see?
Mayank: No need, nothing, nothing.
Mayank: Create as much classes as you can, it is much better.
Hardik Vora: Gotcha.
Mayank: Usme hardly koi Parikh Patekar other jytnyet shivam classes manaje jytnya jytnya in depth.
Mayank: Oh, I hired you.
Mayank: Prabhakaranagar.
Hardik Vora: And first question, I also try to relate response structure when we were discussing structured output, we stored it. So that use case I understood because of his experience.
Hardik Vora: So, the response is based on the structure of the response.
Mayank: Easy problem.
Hardik Vora: Malab bhamko usko tweet kar.
Mayank: Then we can have, again, either middleware or something jaapiya mu structure or mu change kar sakte hai. Jaapiya mu pass na kari aur jaap after model, jaap before model call j.
Hardik Vora: Mmhm.
Mayank: Osmium change karthik. Uggi model koi finally.
Hardik Vora: Correct. Quick use.
Mayank: Oh, it's all.
Hardik Vora: Oh.
Mayank: Yeah, exactly.
Mayank: ki bhai tipogar kochhna pul lagre aisa hai toh yuskarun nahi toh matkarot.
Hardik Vora: To conditional vishalaganaya. I mean.
Mayank: Ideally, yes, that would be a much better approach, ko ki phira pass mat karo. Jabab ko lagte hai gi mein mujhe chaayos kis mein, wo I think mein k.
Hardik Vora: Mmhm.
Mayank: We must have done this for the middleware. Jitra in-depth of the middleware Paldhiana. Som kujmi ka siya kya?
Mayank: I don't know if it's complex or not, but complexity is at no level. People use LangChain and LangGraph to create proper agents of jobs and everything, so I don't know.
Hardik Vora: All right. And my question, I mean, I mean, nobody's there for hand raising or lobby.
Mayank: Nahi habhi to koi nahi hai. Deepanjan, I was waiting for your…
Mayank: So I'm going to put code vivejita for the karan k.
Debanjan Mani_Laptop: Oh, okay.
Mayank: Let's try to fix it. Oh, sorry, Hardik. Sorry, Hardik.
Hardik Vora: So I was unlucky today. I didn't get that because it is very important I try to understand that data science or big data or data engineering concepts will not be able to understand in detail end to end.
Mayank: Data engineering is very important. 60, 70% of the job you do is data engineering in any company.
Mayank: Without realizing.
Hardik Vora: And, I, but it is very relevant to say, conversation and what also highlighted and is very bad, in such case.
Mayank: I think that is the sort of fine rubric anyways, that is totally on people.
Mayank: I understand that, actually.
Mayank: We are doing because we are getting, I could give it on LinkedIn as well. We are giving to you so that we are not getting anything out of it.
Hardik Vora: importance I think I'm not getting it I would request everyone ki just apply ki please return kar refund karwaj so that we can learn such good things and really appreciate aapne jo videos sometimes I go through those you share the link open alternative aapne jo kal I just saw recently yesterday.
Mayank: Oh.
Hardik Vora: Okay.
Mayank: Shorts, correct?
Hardik Vora: Hashwat Svada. So open alternative. What is the actual difference?
Mayank: Meshto is different. Meshto is kind of… I guess.
Hardik Vora: Mmh.
Mayank: Open alternative tool, it tells you the free one. For example, Claude Code, it tells you the free one. It tells you the AI ka ka ka ka free approach. It tells you the AI ka ka ka ka ka ka ka ka ka ka ka ka ka ka ka ka ka AI ka ka ka ka ka ka ka ka ka ka ka ka ka ka ka ka ka ka ka ka ka ka ka ka ka ka ka ka ka ka k.
Mayank: Claude Code, Claude Code. So that is the…
Hardik Vora: Freewelly you mean? Freewelly you mean.
Mayank: What kovaka bhiyuni.
Hardik Vora: Correct me, Kurthop.
Mayank: There is a free alternative with which if you enter your key, open work is there just as an example.
Hardik Vora: Open Work.
Mayank: Exactly, it is almost the same.
Hardik Vora: Okay.
Mayank: It just tells you those free alternatives.
Mayank: So AIC cost koi bhi se unlimited fee nahi d.
Mayank: Yeah, he's always charging, but I'm going to.
Mayank: That said, there are multiple chiso jaatiya, right? Claude Code is free. There is no open code there which is free.
Hardik Vora: Huh, I usually do use the same thing.
Mayank: So, this is a very useful use case. Exactly, I'm going to show you the website. This is a pretty good website. I'm going to show you the SARI tools. Even DB wala bhi dekho gee, I'm going to show you the free version available. So, it's free, of course. I'm going to show you the free version.
Hardik Vora: Mmhm.
Mayank: I think at least till you file, find very nice applications for the use case. If you look at what paid features you have, you will be free to use the app. For example, if you look at Gmail, you will be able to see that the app is available to the client for free. So that was the tool. AI level has better limits, but not the exact total complete freedom.
Hardik Vora: Needing it.
Mayank: No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Hardik Vora: Pawarapnejju nurgu kalyan bola, so mayank usme, it's free to link and then it stores everything kya? Jawapne.
Mayank: Oh, oh, oh.
Hardik Vora: So I'm just trying to relate now. So now I am integrating with Nuruk LLM. So what kind of, in short, what you are trying to answer, right?
Mayank: So, it's been a long-term memory for me. It's been a long-term memory for me.
Hardik Vora: Right.
Mayank: So, it is majorly for the notebook that we use to store the information.
Hardik Vora: Go internally khud store karthai and optimize khudi karthai, so we don't have the control, correct?
Mayank: Oh, would be happy.
Hardik Vora: Date or runtime? Management karne.
Mayank: Exactly.
Hardik Vora: Hmmm.
Mayank: matlab kya bolte hai khud kya yaar saran apa rahega kar kar kar kar kar kar kar kar kar kar kar kar kar kar kar kar kar kar kar.
Hardik Vora: Okay, okay.
Hardik Vora: I'm just going through my questions, Mike, just be.
Mayank: No.
Hardik Vora: All the time, divanjan m.
Mayank: So we can quickly have a look for simple quotes.
Mayank: I think our viewing panelist may know tokar sathyap.
Hardik Vora: And may I ask a question, I mean, generally, generally.
Hardik Vora: Generally, you were mentioning earlier couple of yeah. Doubt link sessions may you should focus mostly on software development lifecycle and not in Agentic Walapat.
Hardik Vora: And I have also seen and heard through LinkedIn, and I'm not sure how much it is through my
Hardik Vora: apa experience bata toh ki agentic applications, agentic applications ja bhanati hai malab I'm not sure people still don't understand yo aapne bhi samhya hai usya anko samhya hai agent ko continuously execute karna usko production mein run karna uskar token optimization malab jo tracing usab jo karna implementation karna hai toh that in real world production grid application only 5% of those are only achievable because of.
Hardik Vora: XYZ reasons, which you are explaining in detail.
Hardik Vora: I mean, as per your understanding, what I have understood, just correct me, ki jo amari use kese kus ko no kodia, low kodia aap ki implementation logic se, we can build our applications and use kese ko implement kar ki integrate kar ki es ko production ais kare. And then if just in case if agentic.
Hardik Vora: ka usage hai, toi si kutna call rahnasiyamne for good end-to-end.
Mayank: No, I haven't cleared it out.
Hardik Vora: Mmhm.
Mayank: So, agent uses software. It's not the other way around. Software uses agents. Plus, there are concepts. More or less, these are just now repackaged concepts. That's the idea. So, the API calls you, right?
Hardik Vora: Hmm. Okay.
Mayank: Oscar onlysarifisoria.
Hardik Vora: Right.
Mayank: Ka bhijs nahi API call bhijs hijs hijs kar.
Hardik Vora: Mmhm.
Mayank: That person would be a much better candidate, rather than the other case.
Mayank: Ankur, jesse mi middlewear, right? It's not a new concept. The reason I'm able to tell this much depth is kya kya normally mi apa.
Hardik Vora: okay.
Mayank: So, the benefit becomes that… Sorry. The benefit becomes that the software lifecycle is very clear.
Hardik Vora: Mmhm.
Mayank: He is much better as a candidate, kuch ki wo langchain langrabhiso samajhlega.
Hardik Vora: Mmm.
Mayank: Versus vice versa. I think the middleware is a little bit more difficult to understand.
Mayank: Take a look at this.
Hardik Vora: Mmm.
Mayank: Dekhna uskum asam jana chauhan kya chahte kam kahi se bhi woh yeh naas naas.
Hardik Vora: Mmhm.
Mayank: Thank you.
Mayank: So that is the case model.
Hardik Vora: And, I think,
Mayank: Like, let me try…
Hardik Vora: Correct. So I think.
Mayank: That's.
Hardik Vora: I think yoga, right?
Mayank: Ni mala baisik parayai niy.
Mayank: Not at all.
Hardik Vora: Abju project may jo up.
Mayank: Project me use karak hai. MCP maybe I have created concept jaap hai amne async tool kar kar khi hai.
Hardik Vora: Mmhm.
Mayank: Lekin, samjhani wo maine, samjhani ke liye thoda sa easy se start khanna p.
Hardik Vora: Hmm. Good.
Mayank: MCP.
Hardik Vora: may I say that fast API understanding is very important.
Mayank: No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Hardik Vora: I mean, okay, that is what I was trying to ask.
Mayank: I don't know, APIs are there, APIs are there, APIs are there, APIs are there, API.
Hardik Vora: Thank you.
Mayank: It's a combination of APIs. So, I'm not going to go into the in-depths of the MCP. I'm going to go into the MCP bhoja. Although, honestly, it's useful because it's not used, but that is subjective. Now, it is useful. I'm not going to say it's useful, but I'm going to say it's useful. AIC integrated is useful.
Mayank: So, that we will also discuss, but should be not a problem, but we will be covering it in depth only.
Hardik Vora: And globally, maine ki MCP is… it's overused,
Mayank: Sunny.
Hardik Vora: No.
Mayank: No, it's not overused. It.
Mayank: Normally use. Madhavi ghi vulgar kya sahin hiya lah pagar? Aapko pini application ko AIC Jy.
Hardik Vora: May I ask you a question? Ki bananahi padega, madam, why is…
Mayank: Voila, por mem, si.
Hardik Vora: kyu ki dusre applications ko link karna hai, that is the only purpose, right?
Mayank: I don't know if it's because I don't have a phone.
Hardik Vora: Okay, okay.
Mayank: The properties of the property are not available in the city.
Hardik Vora: Thanks, Mayank, for explaining details.
Hardik Vora: Mande big dita ka agar koupan mileto.
Mayank: Next year, next month I will try. Let's hope bakhil greeting. Let me see everything or kukhana rahmah help ko jaati hai. Reach out to reach out to me karun ki look pad raya roosteri kaise.
Hardik Vora: And my final question, Mehra, ki Claude architecture ka, I mean, I'm hearing with a couple of colleagues as well, ki wo architecture ka certification and all. So how much is it relevant? Should we do it a market meh, just to survive, we should do it on just showing ki ki.
Mayank: Yes, yes.
Hardik Vora: Apne, apne Sikadia.
Mayank: Creating the content in.
Hardik Vora: Hello, your voice dropped me.
Mayank: Hello?
Hardik Vora: Hello? Yeah, yeah.
Mayank: So, for the cloud certificate, I am saying that is based on the companies. Companies, malab kuch companies usko de sakte hai. But the concept kuch mein padhanga ko yehi sab hai. This was me MCP IO in depth. Human in the loop IO gajajin dar kari chahi hai. Concepts ko yehi hai. Was ko cloud level peto. But uskar content bhanangun ho I will try to.
Hardik Vora: Okay, okay.
Mayank: I am creating the content kaafi hatta ka. I am creating the exam kaafi hatta ka. I am creating the batch ka bajj mein bajj ka bajj ka bajj ka bajj ka bajj ka bajj ka bajj ka ba.
Hardik Vora: At.
Mayank: So, kharav loo kho ko ko ko ko ko ko ko k.
Hardik Vora: Okay, okay.
Mayank: kya kya poogi learnings hai kya kya ID the kya certificate kya baare mein padhanay is not in the course but that said, yaha yaha kya kya kya kya kya kya ky.
Mayank: But in my laptop, files are very big. So YouTube best karthik tai hai. So kabhi kabhi di karthik tai jo software joya panna hai. So I will fix that up. Okay? Sure, sure.
Hardik Vora: Sure, sure, thanks.
Mayank: Anything which I create, I will be more than happy. I will not ask any money extra.
Hardik Vora: 2 years.
Mayank: Toh vote ancient matlow. Once I create it, I will be happy to share. In the future, we will have a system designer who will be working on AI system design. That's it.
Hardik Vora: Because it is very, it is not end to end.
Mayank: Naiv ko nahi patal ho ko ko rasme ho ishuwati ki make k.
Mayank: So, no worries. As soon as I get it, I will do that. Let me see. I think it's available. So, let's see how many people are rating it up. So, if you have any requirement or help, please reach out to me. So, no worries. I will try. If you have any resources over the next four or five months we are together, you will be getting all of them. Thank you.
Hardik Vora: Yeah, I really appreciated your efforts.
Mayank: Yeah, no worries.
Hardik Vora: Thanks.
Mayank: Thank you. Devanjay?
Debanjan Mani_Laptop: Thank you.
Mayank: The list of.
Debanjan Mani_Laptop: Actually…
Mayank: For the Lord.
Debanjan Mani_Laptop: I, no, no, no, that's all. I, yeah, actually, my computer is running very slow and there are lots of windows open.
Mayank: Sir, no worries. Just try to fix it up yourself. If you face any issues, just let me know tomorrow. We will fix it up.
Debanjan Mani_Laptop: Yeah, I, I mean, I should not have, should not be, present problems, anymore. I will do that force reinstall.
Mayank: Just reinstall it first and else just create a new environment. Either use PIP or something, maybe if you are comfortable with that. And then run your code. Just one thing, also check that the environment which you are using on your file in your Jupyter notebook, that is the right one, because that can also be wrong one, okay?
Debanjan Mani_Laptop: No, it's the same appointment.
Mayank: Let's just try to then fix it. I don't think this simple code will face any issues because then I think we will have to reinstall everything because maybe some in the backend, sometime it happens that over it or something like files, new library, something like it was very, very rare, but sometime it still happens. And rather than solving it, the best approach is to delete everything and reinstall it on Windows or anywhere. So that would be much pretty simple as well.
Debanjan Mani_Laptop: Okay, okay, let me, let me just.
Mayank: Yeah, let me know. Nik, you can ask your doubt.
Nik: Yeah, hi, Mayank. So, Mayank, I just have a question. So, like, Mayank, like, do you have any WhatsApp group and all, like, where you are sharing all these coupon.
Mayank: India, I'm sharing here only nothing else. Yeah, in the chat or in that craft link which I've shared with all of you. No.
Nik: Okay.
Mayank: No, sir. Nothing else. Nothing else is.
Nik: I think I pulled through the screen, guys.
Mayank: Huh?
Nik: Yeah, I'll be on time soon.
Mayank: Okay.
Nik: Yeah, I got it.
Mayank: Good.
Mayank: Thanks a lot, everyone. Let's speak soon. By.